<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Tangle]]></title><description><![CDATA[Tangle is the personal knowledge graph. Tangle empowers everyone to capture and connect thoughts to create big ideas.]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com./</link><image><url>http://usetangle.com.//logos/logo-512.png</url><title>Tangle</title><link>http://usetangle.com./</link></image><generator>GatsbyJS Material Starter</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 22:52:56 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://usetangle.com.//rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><author><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></author><copyright><![CDATA[Copyright © 2018. Hex Ventures]]></copyright><item><title><![CDATA[Alpha How To Guide]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hi there!   This page is the dedicated "How-to Guide" for Tangle. We will be updating it as we roll out new features and will let you when…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-guide</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-guide</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hi there!&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page is the dedicated &quot;How-to Guide&quot; for Tangle. We will be updating it as we roll out new features and will let you when we do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;taking-a-note&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#taking-a-note&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Taking a note&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click the big orange plus button in the top left or the &quot;Create a new note&quot; button on the right of the home screen and get writing!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can use all the normal rich text editing shortcuts or use markdown -- there is a Markdown cheat sheet at the bottom of the editor  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;importing-from-evernote&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#importing-from-evernote&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Importing from Evernote&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can import notes from Evernote by going to your Evernote app on your computer and selecting a notebook or notes you would like to have in Tangle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Evernote, Click File --&gt; Export notes --&gt; Save (make sure format is set to HTML)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Here is an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-export-Evernote-notes&quot;&gt;in-depth walkthrough from Quora&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then, head to Tangle and click the upload button in the navigation bar on the left (it looks like an up arrow)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, select the HTML files you just exported from Evernote and voila!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two things to note:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The maximum amount of data you can import to Tangle is 1MB/note or 50MB total&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Images are not supported by Tangle yet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;searching&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#searching&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Searching&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search for anything your heart desires in the search bar in the top right-hand corner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can also search without leaving your writing experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;visualizing-your-connections&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#visualizing-your-connections&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Visualizing your connections&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Related notes will begin to appear on the right-hand side of a note you are writing as soon as Tangle finds a connection!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click Visualize at any time -- on the home screen, on a given note, or search results -- to visualize the connections between your writing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Connected Notebook]]></title><description><![CDATA[Do your notes generate ideas? There is a connectivity problem with today’s digital notebooks. As Tiago explains in  P.A.R.A. III: Building…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-connected-notebook</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-connected-notebook</guid><category><![CDATA[Tangle]]></category><category><![CDATA[Connected]]></category><category><![CDATA[Demo]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h3 id=&quot;do-your-notes-generate-ideas&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#do-your-notes-generate-ideas&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Do your notes generate ideas?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a connectivity problem with today’s digital notebooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Tiago explains in &lt;a href=&quot;https://praxis.fortelabs.co/p-a-r-a-iii-building-an-idea-generator-400347ef3bb6/&quot;&gt;P.A.R.A. III: Building an Idea Generator&lt;/a&gt;, organizational methods for retrieving ideas from note-taking applications rely on imposing structure. A structure is necessary because of the hierarchical nature of knowledge management software, namely note-taking apps. Maintaining the proper hierarchy is burdensome, yet failure to do so reduces, if not eliminates, your notes’ future value. Impose too much order, however, and you’ll reduce the opportunity for the serendipitous connections that make you creative and help generate new ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tiago and his team identified this problem and took action. They developed &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/fortelabs/evernote-random&quot;&gt;RandomNote&lt;/a&gt;, an application that adds randomness into your workflow by retrieving, as its name suggests, a random note from Evernote when you click it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The app &lt;em&gt;“allows notes in different notebooks to encounter each other,”&lt;/em&gt; helping to shine light on unidentified connections and revealing new ideas. RandomNote is a great hack for those moments you feel “stuck” on something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RandomNote is undoubtedly an effective tool, but look closer and you’ll find it suggests much larger questions about current note-taking software. Why should we rely solely on serendipity and luck to inspire connections and resurface old thoughts? What if we could make connection more &lt;em&gt;purposeful&lt;/em&gt;? We are building Tangle to do just that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tangle is a complete overhaul of traditional note-taking technology that puts principles of discoverability and connectivity first.&lt;/strong&gt; To accomplish this, we have rethought the data structure of current digital note-taking tools. Instead of using a hierarchical structure, &lt;strong&gt;Tangle uses one built for connection: a graph.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The graph database enables Tangle to be a &lt;strong&gt;connection-first notebook&lt;/strong&gt; that elevates idea generation and enhances the creative process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-a-graph&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-is-a-graph&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;What is a graph?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graphs are great for modeling data that have many &lt;em&gt;relationships&lt;/em&gt;. Graphs contain two types of data: nodes and edges. A node is something like a person, company, or city. Nodes are described with properties and labels, and they are relatable in some way to another node. Edges represent those relationships. They are described with unique properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nodes are &lt;em&gt;things&lt;/em&gt; that are relatable. Edges are &lt;em&gt;relationships&lt;/em&gt; between them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take the following example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two &lt;em&gt;Giraffes&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Edward and Norton&lt;/strong&gt;, are friends. Both &lt;strong&gt;Edward&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Norton&lt;/strong&gt; eats the &lt;em&gt;fruit&lt;/em&gt;, apricots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/usetangle-static-assets/blog/graph_example.png&quot; alt=&quot;giraffe&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sentence is a domain in which we have Giraffe nodes, “Edward” and “Norton”, a fruit node, “apricot”, and the relationships between them, “friends” and “enjoy eating.” By taking this statement, and identifying the relevant components, one can begin to build a model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why can’t we just use a normal database to do this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core reason is that traditional &lt;strong&gt;SQL and other noSQL databases cannot scale effectively to handle these kinds of relationships&lt;/strong&gt;. When traversing thousands of relationships, SQL databases must do something called foreign key lookups. These lookups require the database to go to an index, which is essentially a file stored somewhere in your database. You can imagine that on average, this SQL operation takes X milliseconds when following a single relationship. If you want to traverse 10,000 relationships, it would take X*10,000 milliseconds. This is not ideal for data with a lot of relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Native graph databases like &lt;a href=&quot;https://neo4j.com/&quot;&gt;Neo4j&lt;/a&gt; use a technique called index-free adjacency to solve this problem. Neo4j stores references to other records as pointers from a starting record, rather than in an index of foreign keys located in a database. &lt;strong&gt;When performing deep traversals on large datasets in a graph, problems that previously took hours can take milliseconds.&lt;/strong&gt; This is profound, and its enabling us to power a model of connection at breakneck speed. If you’d like to learn more, check out this &lt;a href=&quot;https://neo4j.com/blog/why-graph-databases-are-the-future/&quot;&gt;Neo4j article&lt;/a&gt; that dives deeper into the power of graph databases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-note-graph&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-note-graph&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The note-graph&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tangle uses the power of the graph database to enable real-time connections between your notes. You could not use a SQL data structure and hope to achieve the same level of performance. What we end up with is something more akin to a &lt;em&gt;note-graph&lt;/em&gt; than a traditional notebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because Tangle’s graph stores the relationships between your notes, we are able to &lt;strong&gt;abstract away any need for manual organization&lt;/strong&gt;. Anytime you capture a thought or take a note in Tangle, it automatically shows you the connections to any of your related content. You do no work to surface these connections; Tangle takes care of it for you instantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll walk you through what this looks like in practice with a couple GIFs. In the first one below, I have a new note open, or what we call a “collection.” The collection, on the left, is a collection of related notes and thoughts I have captured — as you can tell by the title, this one is about the World Cup. As I capture different thoughts about the games, players, and my sadness at the United States’ failure to qualify, related captures I have written previously start to pop up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
          &lt;div
            class=&quot;gatsby-resp-iframe-wrapper&quot;
            style=&quot;padding-bottom: 54.0625%; position: relative; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&quot;
          &gt;
            &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/278735859&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen style=&quot;
            position: absolute;
            top: 0;
            left: 0;
            width: 100%;
            height: 100%;
          &quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does this work? Tangle analyzes the text using natural language processing — a type of machine learning that enables computers to understand language. In milliseconds, Tangle absorbs the content and traverses the graph, looking for other notes to which the original might have a connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
          &lt;div
            class=&quot;gatsby-resp-iframe-wrapper&quot;
            style=&quot;padding-bottom: 54.0625%; position: relative; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&quot;
          &gt;
            &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/278735643&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen style=&quot;
            position: absolute;
            top: 0;
            left: 0;
            width: 100%;
            height: 100%;
          &quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The environment Tangle creates is connection-first. It’s goal is to surface your related content when it might be useful to you. We believe that this opens up a new paradigm of enhanced creativity and productivity. No need to spend time on strict organizational structures to get the most out of your notes, no workflow disruption searching for notes you have already taken, and no more time-sink researching something online that might be hidden in your folder structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;so-whats-next&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#so-whats-next&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;So what’s next?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are currently hard at work improving Tangle and are looking for feedback. If you are someone at the intersection of knowledge management and technology (and like trying new tech) we would love for you to participate in our alpha release. There is still time — we will be launching to select users over the next few weeks. Want to be one of them? &lt;a href=&quot;https://ventures.us17.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=710569ad280cf37e55faa0612&amp;#x26;id=1f711ff76c&quot;&gt;Sign up here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tangle team also distributes a weekly newsletter providing development updates, KM blog posts, as well as other inspiring content from around the web. &lt;a href=&quot;http://eepurl.com/djoBb5&quot;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to keep in touch with us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, if you’d like to get in touch directly, please feel free to email info@usetangle.com with any questions, comments, suggestions, or any bit of general feedback. We are open to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading and thank you to the Praxis team for letting us share Tangle with you.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[An Idea for a Personal Insight Engine]]></title><description><![CDATA[Data visualization is all the rage and for good reason. Technology that allows a user to transform data into a digestible format is valuable…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-idea-personal-insight</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-idea-personal-insight</guid><category><![CDATA[Idea]]></category><category><![CDATA[Insight]]></category><category><![CDATA[Engine]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Data visualization is all the rage and for good reason. Technology that allows a user to transform data into a digestible format is valuable. A massive spreadsheet of numbers suddenly becomes digestible, helping decision makers in companies more easily grasp historical trends and better predict the future of their businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repackaging data into bar graphs, histograms, and bubble plots has become big business. According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/brandfeatures/venture-capital/article?id=5619&quot;&gt;Reuters and Stratistics MRC&lt;/a&gt;, the Global Business Intelligence (BI) market is expected to grow from $15.64 billion in 2016 to reach $29.48 billion by 2022. Companies clearly put a high value on understanding themselves, where they have been, what they have done, and where they are going. The BI market has exploded because they empower the enterprise to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what about the individual? We the people are constantly creating data, leaving breadcrumbs that could be gobbled up and digested for the same purpose: to gain a better understanding of ourselves. Advertisers and marketers already do this for their own benefit with your &lt;em&gt;cookie crumbs&lt;/em&gt; — segmenting internet users based on their behavior and serving ads against that data. But the personal breadcrumbs you leave should, and can, benefit you as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The emails you send, tweets you tweet, and documents you create are all pieces of unstructured data that contextualize &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; over time. Repackaging your data into a digestible format would help &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; better understand &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;, just like how BI tools help business leaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you remember what topics you were interested in, what events you were talking about, or what content you were creating five years ago? Last year? Last month? The evolution of your life, both professional and personal, is constant. Connecting your personal dots to concretize that evolution would be a useful tool on many levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turning your breadcrumbs into personal insights is something we have been thinking about recently. And we have come up with a couple ideas that we think could be useful personal insights (PI).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;clustering&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#clustering&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Clustering&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding how the concepts and topics in your content are related would be highly useful to anyone trying to zoom out and take a snapshot of themself today, or anytime in the past. The easiest way to take that meta-photo is to use clustering algorithms. Clustering algorithms allow us to help answer the question: what ideas, people, or concepts are the glue between the content you are creating? What is the main connector between those dots?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clustering divides data into groups such that those data points in the same group are more similar to other data points in that group than those in other groups. In simple words, the aim is to segregate groups with similar traits and assign them into clusters. Those clusters define the relationship between data points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In practice, you can imagine a visualization that segregates your network into clusters based on your interactions with those people via email or what notes you have written that are related to them. Seeing those clusters might help you more intuitively understand how the people in your network are connected, or how best to actually connect them in reality. You can see this concept below using Facebook data:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/usetangle-static-assets/blog/social-graph.png&quot; alt=&quot;social-graph&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;chronological-insights&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chronological-insights&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Chronological insights&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Information management systems currently allow you to organize files in linear hierarchies. First, you organize files into folders normally based on some principle. You can then view those files alphabetically, oldest to newest newest-oldest, content format, and content size, just to name a few.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The benefit of this structure is that you are able to organize things to your liking. They are also searchable and (most of the time) the document you are looking for will be returned to you. But structuring content this way does not give you much more than that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, imagine you could plot your content -- your emails, tweets, documents, notes -- on an X and Y axis. The X axis is time and the Y axis is any measurable metric you would like. Take relevancy or saliency for example. You could drill down on the core concepts in your life, compare them, and learn how they change over time based on those principle metrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like businesses reflect on backward looking data to make better forward-looking decisions, wouldn’t it be useful to have a personal dashboard to better understand yourself, what you have done, and how that is changing over time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-personal-insight-engine&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#a-personal-insight-engine&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A personal insight engine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clustering&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Chronological Insights&lt;/strong&gt; are just two examples of real-time qualitative self-analytics (buzzwords!). Until recently, we haven’t had the tools to digest your personal breadcrumbs and turn them into a more holistic view of the self. I personally am compelled by the the idea of a personal dashboard. I have breadcrumbs scattered across data silos that might demystify the path I have taken to where I am now and clarify my experience and what I know; &lt;strong&gt;my knowledge.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you agree? I would love to hear your thoughts on the idea or for other ways to visualize your content in the name of self-analytics. Shoot me a note at myles@usetangle.com!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[6 Universal Lessons I‘ve Learned As A Founder]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today is a great day for a blog post. June 22, 2018 marks 6 months since I set up an LLC with my co-founder, Cameron, and began my foray…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-6-universal-lessons</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-6-universal-lessons</guid><category><![CDATA[Founder]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lessons]]></category><category><![CDATA[Learning]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Today is a great day for a blog post. June 22, 2018 marks 6 months since I set up an LLC with my co-founder, Cameron, and began my foray into startup land. Six months feels like yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t notice the anniversary until Thursday, but over the past 24 hours, I have taken some time to reflect. A lot has changed for me. A lot has stayed the same. Here are some things I captured when I was brainstorming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I no longer have an income&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I spend far less&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I work far more hours per week than I did at my last job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I still find time to workout and play soccer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cameron’s ping pong skills have improved greatly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I still beat him… sometimes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I watch a lot less TV&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I read a lot more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I write a lot more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am having fun like I always do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have far less stability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am learning more than ever&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That last point, &lt;em&gt;learning&lt;/em&gt;, made me pause. I realized over the last day that I have gained a lot of knowledge I did not have six months ago. A side-effect of needing to constantly figure stuff out I suppose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was that &lt;em&gt;stuff&lt;/em&gt;, though? I realized I hadn’t really been keeping track. I had no syllabus except a paper trail of Google Docs, PowerPoints, call notes, incorporation documents, Slack notifications, and bank statements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set out to piece together the last six months. I wanted to fit together those pieces to better crystallize my learnings. Transferring the lessons from my head to the page would make them more concrete, tangible, and usable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found many lessons hiding in plain site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For one, don’t have an introductory meeting with a corporate law firm without knowing exactly what you want and ensuring they know what a start-up is. They’ll get confused and charge you for their confusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always double check code you run that you didn’t write. Run a third party’s startup script and next thing you know you might accidentally wipe your database. Don’t worry, we have righted this wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I looked back at the last half-year, I found plenty of learnings specific to my experiences as a first-time founder like those two. But I also found more universal lessons — things I would have wanted to know as a newly graduated 22 year old going into finance. I probably implicitly knew the value of these lessons during the first three years of my professional life, but #startuplife has undoubtedly magnified their importance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 6 universal lessons, one for each month, that I felt compelled to share. Maybe you have seen a version of them before, maybe you have not. Either way, here are some snack-able chunks of wisdom to chew on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;over-communicate&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#over-communicate&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Over-communicate&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nobody knows what you are thinking, even your co-founders who sit in the same room with you all day. Communicating effectively is really hard. When we working at Tangle, headphones are often on and we are locked in. Particularly when Cameron and Cole are coding, conversation takes a back seat. I am researching, creating materials, editing copy, or talking with potential users. It’s hard to stay on the same page even as a three person team. A lot of it has to do with trying to move fast. It’s hard to hear each other when you are each in your own B-52.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We learned the consequences of this the hard way, as I think many people, not just founders do too. A few weeks ago, it became clear that the pain points each of us thought Tangle would solve were different. I thought one thing, Cameron another, and Cole a hybrid. Our vision for the company was not in sync. How the in the world could that happen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took 14 hours of conversation to realign Tangle’s stars. We lost a full day. I remember in my two other jobs in finance and consulting similar, but less severe situations occurring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Wait, you aren’t working on updating the cap table?” I remember an associating asking me during my analyst days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“No, was I meant to be?” Was not the right response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how can you over-communicate, whether it be on the vision of a product, goal-setting or task management? Share early and share often. Information symmetry allows everyone to act optimally. The more optimally your colleagues can act, the better the work product, and (theoretically) the more money the company will make. That is good for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing we have done at Tangle to help this is move our goals, tasks, product documents, and user pain points out of the digital and onto whiteboards that are in plain site. Things get lost in shared drives. You forget to look at them, organize them, and update them. All of a sudden they are stale and your vision for what you are doing is blurry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping a written, explicit explanation of our goals for the week and month, our product vision and principles, and what problems the product solves in plain site keeps them permanently top-of-mind. It allows us to constantly be questioning what we are doing with the bigger picture in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;read&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#read&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Read&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never used to read. It was never a habit I formed outside of being forced to do it for school. What a shame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reason I never formed the habit was because reading seemed like work. Work that was always more scary than watching or listening to stuff. It is probably because reading is active. Watching and listening are passive. The marginal extra benefit of reading a book, though, far outweighs the marginal cost. I wish I understood those economics earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tangle has a book club, and that book club has helped me to form the healthy habit of reading. We read a book every two weeks or so and spend 30 minutes discussing it via a Slack call or in-person if we are all together. That exercise alone has brought me immense learning. It has made me more interesting and thoughtful at work. I have found myself often applying learnings from the books we read to my deliverables. It has also made me more interesting in my social life. It turns out that dating a guy that reads is “sexy.” Who knew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a smattering of the books I have read with the group and by myself:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00TT1VLAO/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;#x26;btkr=1&quot;&gt;Why Information Grows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Brotopia-Breaking-Boys-Silicon-Valley-ebook/dp/B074LQKJJC/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;#x26;ie=UTF8&amp;#x26;qid=1529688319&amp;#x26;sr=1-1&amp;#x26;keywords=brotopia+breaking+up+the+boys%27+club+of+silicon+valley&quot;&gt;Brotopia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B078FZ9SYB/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;#x26;btkr=1&quot;&gt;Measure What Matters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Writing-Well-30th-Anniversary-Nonfiction-ebook/dp/B0090RVGW0/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;#x26;ie=UTF8&amp;#x26;qid=1529688417&amp;#x26;sr=1-1&amp;#x26;keywords=on+writing+well&quot;&gt;On Writing Well&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Bad-Blood-Secrets-Silicon-Startup/dp/152473165X&quot;&gt;Bad Blood: Secrets and Lies in a Silicon Valley Start-up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Algorithms-Live-Computer-Science-Decisions-ebook/dp/B015CKNWJI/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;#x26;ie=UTF8&amp;#x26;qid=1529688541&amp;#x26;sr=1-1&amp;#x26;keywords=algorithms+to+live+by&quot;&gt;Algorithms to Live By&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/How-Win-Friends-Influence-People-ebook/dp/B003WEAI4E/ref=sr_1_3?s=digital-text&amp;#x26;ie=UTF8&amp;#x26;qid=1529689868&amp;#x26;sr=1-3&amp;#x26;keywords=how+to+win+friends+and+influence+people&quot;&gt;How to Win Friends and Influence People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;write&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#write&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Write&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Writing is thinking. To write well is to think clearly. That’s why it’s so hard.” - David McCullough&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do a lot of writing now. More than ever, actually. More than in high school and more than in college, where I wrote constantly for class assignments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always liked writing, but never knew how hard it was. I think this is because I never &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; wrote well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The better you can write about something, the better you understand something. The better I understand Tangle’s go-to-market strategy, our future customer’s pain points, the technology that Cameron and Cole are implementing to solve them, and even my own frustrations the better I can write about them. So I am practicing. Practicing everyday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sure you are busy. I am sure there are many things ahead of writing in your personal stack ranking. My recommendation is to move “spend time writing,” up on that list. No matter what you do, writing about it will help clarify your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish I wrote more about the problems I was tackling on behalf of my client during my consulting engagement. I was acting as a go-between evaluating a partnership with a company using blockchain technology to solve advertising fraud. Spending time writing coherently about what the heck a blockchain is might have helped my client better understand the opportunity and how to move forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more you can write things down in a clear and concise manner, the more clearly you can think. I have found it is a lot like flexing a muscle. The more you do it, the stronger and more flexible that muscle will become. Try writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;make-the-most-of-lulls&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#make-the-most-of-lulls&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Make the most of lulls&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In every job there are lulls. Even a founder’s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are times that I am blocked. Cole taught me that word. You probably intuitively know what blocked means, but to be clear, it is when someone else is still working on something that needs to be complete for you to finish what you are working on. I currently can’t finish writing a guest post for a productivity blog because we haven’t finished a UI revamp and we want to insert some GIFs of the product. I am blocked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can make the most of lulls and blocks, however. I never used to think about this and wish I did. I bet at your job there are times during the day where you just aren’t doing much. How do you spend that time? Just think about the low hanging fruits you could pick when you are “chilling at work.” I bet there are a bunch and I bet they will taste sweet. I have no specifics to recommend here except to think about this the next time it happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;always-have-a-goal-in-mind-for-meetings&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#always-have-a-goal-in-mind-for-meetings&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Always have a goal in mind for meetings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson comes from a specific situation, but is so relevant. Cameron and I (Cole was in SF at the time) had a meeting with a partner at a venture capital firm. We had already met with him once before and this follow-up was meant to be somewhat of an update chat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We didn’t go into the meeting with a clear goal, however, and when our 30 minutes was coming to an end, I found myself stuttering after he asked “So what can I be helpful with?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cameron saved the day by jumping in, but we both came away from the meeting knowing we had screwed up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a goal in mind when you have a meeting, no matter how formal or informal. Meetings can be such a &amp;#x26;*#@. They take you away from your work and are often more costly than helpful. The other party (or parties) will appreciate your clear intentions and your conversations will be much more effective too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Catching-up” just isn’t a useful reason to meet during a work day. Friends do that on Saturday afternoons in the park. It is a really easy thing to do, but I think a lot of people screw it up, including me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;get-out-of-the-weeds&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#get-out-of-the-weeds&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Get out of the weeds&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tidbit is an offshoot of the first five learnings but I think it deserves its own section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is incredibly difficult to think about something really hard, to research it, to write about it, and to constantly be talking about it without getting lost. Work is a process. There is a big difference, though, in simply being a part of the process, and understanding why you are part of the process and &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; that process is in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, this blog post is part of my process. I write one per week. The process began because we thought writing blog posts and sharing them would help attract a following of sorts. A marketing tool and a useful way to stay in touch with those that might be interested in what we are doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently though I got lost. Why I was writing was no longer clear. All I could see were trees, no forest. I recalibrated by asking Cameron and Cole why they thought I was writing the blog posts. It was a great exercise and helped me to regain my perspective. It also unveiled a problem that I hadn’t thought about: I wasn’t measuring how much the blog was driving people to our site. Was my writing even worth my time? Was it worth the company’s time? That problem has since been rectified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish I asked this question at my previous job more often. Asking why you are doing something can be the most valuable, hardest, and easiest thing you’ll ever do.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Importance of Forgetting]]></title><description><![CDATA[Imagine your brain is a computer. You are ingesting data every second of your life. The data are all different formats: smells, sounds…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-the-importance-of-forgetting</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-the-importance-of-forgetting</guid><category><![CDATA[Memory]]></category><category><![CDATA[Learning]]></category><category><![CDATA[Forgetting]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Imagine your brain is a computer. You are ingesting data every second of your life. The data are all different formats: smells, sounds, feelings, sights. There is no process for you to store this data except to put it into folders on your hard drive. Soon enough, your RAM is exploding, you can no longer function, and you are forced to &lt;em&gt;delete, delete, delete&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/hex-blog-assets/elephant.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;elephant&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://usetangle.com/blog-ai-meets-your-notebook&quot;&gt;In my last post&lt;/a&gt; I discussed the strengths of a machine: they are great at processing problems with specific inputs, outputs and rules. A normal computer, though, would have a torrid time dealing with the problem of processing and storing the data of life, let alone enough physical hard drive space to store it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, human memory storage dwarfs that of a normal computer’s. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/new-estimate-boosts-the-human-brain-s-memory-capacity-10-fold/&quot;&gt;Estimates say we have the capacity for something like a quadrillion bytes.&lt;/a&gt; Your laptop holds on average 5 gigabytes. A quadrillion is 10¹⁵. A gigabyte is 10⁹. Your memory has a lot more bytes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem your memory solves every day is not storing life’s data, but organizing it. You might think of the reason for your forgetfulness as your memory running out of space, a new memory pushes an old memory out, or that a memory was auto-deleted because “your startup disc is almost full.” &lt;em&gt;So frustrating!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that is not quite right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, think of your memory bank as a long shelf. The shelf can fit infinite memories on it. Each memory is searchable but takes a certain amount of time to retrieve. The time it takes is based on where it is placed and how much stuff is already on the shelf. A great memory organ has the most important memories right at the front, closest to you, so you can retrieve them quickly and easily. The less important stuff is further back. More forgotten and out of the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flexibility of your mind is what allows you to judge what information to store and what not to store; forgetting things is paramount because it separates what is important and what is not. Forgetting is crucial for remembering, learning and, living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-forgetting-curve&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-forgetting-curve&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The forgetting curve&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a mathematical function for how we forget things. It’s called the Ebbinghaus Forgetting Curve. It makes you remember that forgetting happens for a reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hermann Ebbinghaus began studying memory in the late 19th century hoping to apply the same mathematical rigor of the physical sciences to the mind. He began by memorizing random strings of nonsense syllables and would test himself on those lists from previous days. He was able to quantify what we all know intuitively: the number of items one can accurately recall goes down as time passes. It looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/hex-blog-assets/curve.png&quot; alt=&quot;curve&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His findings, however, left open many questions. Is this curve a good thing? And, why this curve in particular?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not until about 30 years ago when a Carnegie Mellon professor named John Anderson was studying library retrieval systems did we have a breakthrough. His take on memory connected the principles of his two disciplines, computer science and psychology. He surmised that “the key to a good human memory becomes the same as the key to a good computer cache: predicting which items are most likely to be wanted in the future.¹”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your brain is good at predicting the future value of the data we ingest, and places it in your memory bank accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He came up with the shelf metaphor already mentioned, and conceptualized a good memory organ would be one that keeps handy memories closer to the front of the shelf, and pushes the less valuable memories further back, in essence &lt;em&gt;forgetting them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anderson actually proved this by relating the curve to the real world. He and a colleague, Lael Schooler, performed Ebbinghaus-like studies not on human minds, but on society as a whole. His aim was to determine what patterns characterize the way the world itself “forgets” — the way that events and references fade over time. Anderson and Schooler looked at three human environments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Headlines from the New York Times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recordings of parents talking to their children&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anderson’s own email inbox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all three domains, “a word was found to be more likely to appear again immediately after it had been used, and that the likelihood of seeing it again falls off as time goes on.” This finding is astounding. It showed that reality itself has a statistical structure that mimics the Ebbinghaus curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way we forget things, then, is optimal. &lt;strong&gt;Your memory is tuned precisely to the frequency of your surroundings, organizing your memory so that we are able to remember what’s useful when we most likely need it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a step back and chew on this for a moment. What if you could remember every second of every day that you have ever lived? Those memories were always at the very front of your memory bank, easily experienced again and again. Would you want that power? Or would it be a burden?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are people that have this ability, and it is far from ideal for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amanda Price is one of those people. She is the first person to be diagnosed with what is now known as Highly Superior Autobiographical Memory, or HSAM, a condition she shares with around 60 known others. In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/science/2017/feb/08/total-recall-the-people-who-never-forget&quot;&gt;New York Times article&lt;/a&gt;, she describes how “she can remember most of the days of her life as clearly as the rest of us remember the recent past, with a mixture of broad strokes and sharp detail.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HSAM makes traversing the metaphorical shelf too easy. Every bit of information is right at an afflicted person’s fingertips, just waiting to be surfaced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is, she says, like living with a split screen: on the left side is the present, on the right is a constantly rolling reel of memories, each one sparked by the appearance of present-day stimuli. With so many memories always at the ready, Price says, it can be maddening: virtually anything she sees or hears can be a potential trigger.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is paralyzing for Price. She lives in perpetual fear of any bad decision or hurtful experience because instead of learning and moving on from painful moments in her life, she continues to relive them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An unfortunate superpower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;learn-to-forget&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#learn-to-forget&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Learn to forget&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forgetting keeps your memory from clutter, helps you to move on, and makes it easier to for your mind to function. Forgetting is core to living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reframing memory this way is helpful to rethink other things too. Particularly the opposite of forgetting, learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning is often confused with rote memorization — swallowing information for the sake of ingestion — which traditional schooling leans towards. Learning does not happen temporally. It is constant. It is not how much stuff we can cram into your noggin, but rather your ability to forget the extraneous, and synthesize information to the core points that are the true marks of learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://praxisblog.co/&quot;&gt;Tiago Forte&lt;/a&gt; puts it perfectly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The brain never stops drawing relationships, making connections, and noticing correlations. You couldn’t stop learning if you wanted to. Knowing that our brain is continuously collecting information, our goal switches from remembering as much as possible, to forgetting as much as possible.²&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t even have to remember to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[1] Christian, Brian; Griffiths, Tom. Algorithms to Live By: The Computer Science of Human Decisions (p. 100). Henry Holt and Co.. Kindle Edition.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[2] Forte, Tiago. Progressive Summarization V: The Faster You Forget, The Faster You Learn.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://praxis.fortelabs.co/progressive-summarization-v-the-faster-you-forget-the-faster-you-learn-916b59a4e00f/&quot;&gt;https://praxis.fortelabs.co/progressive-summarization-v-the-faster-you-forget-the-faster-you-learn-916b59a4e00f/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[AI Meets Your Notebook]]></title><description><![CDATA[We humans are a flexible bunch. We are constantly solving life’s problems; juggling how to deal with our overbearing boss and figuring out…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-ai-meets-your-notebook</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-ai-meets-your-notebook</guid><category><![CDATA[AI]]></category><category><![CDATA[MachineLearning]]></category><category><![CDATA[Notebook]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;We humans are a flexible bunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are constantly solving life’s problems; juggling how to deal with our overbearing boss and figuring out party plans for the weekend. Deciding in milliseconds what words would be best to convey a desired meaning is difficult! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These kinds of problems are &lt;em&gt;ill-defined&lt;/em&gt;. They are considered ill-defined because they do not have a clear set of inputs, outputs, and most importantly, rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machines, on the other hand, are great at solving the opposite: &lt;em&gt;well-defined&lt;/em&gt; problems. Programming a machine with clear inputs, outputs and rules allows it to solve incredibly complex math problems in milliseconds. A difficult calculus problem might seem daunting to us, but the machine eats it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To distill the point, human brains are great at &lt;em&gt;matching patterns&lt;/em&gt; we see everyday to solve problems that are not clearly definable. Machines excel at executing processes to solve problems with a clear set of inputs, outputs, and rules. And it is us, the machine’s creator, that creates the processes the machine uses to solve them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;but-that-paradigm-is-changing&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#but-that-paradigm-is-changing&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;But that paradigm is changing.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machine learning and artificial intelligence are making machines more flexible, &lt;em&gt;more human&lt;/em&gt;. The advent of these technologies improve their ability to solve ill-defined problems. It also means the processes by which machines solve problems, well-defined or not, are no longer designed entirely by humans. The machines learn from the output of a problem and augment their processes accordingly.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hence the name, machine learning.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machine learning models and a slew of intelligent humans are empowering machines to take over for people in many areas previously thought impossible. Just check out Google’s assistant in the video below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
          &lt;div
            class=&quot;gatsby-resp-iframe-wrapper&quot;
            style=&quot;padding-bottom: 56.25%; position: relative; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&quot;
          &gt;
            &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JvbHu_bVa_g&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen style=&quot;
            position: absolute;
            top: 0;
            left: 0;
            width: 100%;
            height: 100%;
          &quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The technologies that make this sci-fi a reality are not exclusive to the biggest companies. They are available to be used by all. Tangle uses them too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem Tangle tackles is one of &lt;strong&gt;note discoverability&lt;/strong&gt;. It is currently difficult, time-consuming, and often frustrating to surface the useful notes in our notebooks that might be helpful to us at any given time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The root of the problem starts with the technology. Today’s note-taking apps are designed as digital storage buckets. They require diligent organization and tender care if we aim to keep the information in those buckets easily findable and accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note-discovery is considered an ill-defined problem. Its inputs are vague. Should we only consider the data in each note, or perhaps the context under which we wrote the note as well? And what of outputs? Are we looking for just one related item, or many? How do we &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; if the surfaced notes are in fact the most related? Finally, the rules are completely subjective. Perhaps one person may draw connections between notes that others would not. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fear not. Applications of machine learning, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.algorithmia.com/introduction-natural-language-processing-nlp/&quot;&gt;natural language processing&lt;/a&gt;, help Tangle learn to be more flexible, making it capable of aiding humans in the note discovery process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tangle’s algorithm searches for, and returns, the set of notes it thinks are related. Right now it understands matching people, places, and things. For example: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“machine learning” = “machine learning”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Albert Einstein” = “Albert Einstein”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been trained to the point where it is smart enough to know &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to return a note because it contains &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; matching word. “The” and “the” would be an unhelpful match. What we want are the important ones. Tangle’s algorithm picks out salient notes, suggesting bits of information that are obviously related, and helpful, but also suggests things we have forgotten or did not realize were related in the first place. In this way, Tangle acts not only as a memory aid, but an idea generator as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With time, Tangle will grow smarter. We can hone its model in a number of ways so that it suggests only the best content possible. One example is to train Tangle using an ontology. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tiger --TYPE&lt;em&gt;OF--&gt; Cat --TYPE&lt;/em&gt;OF--&gt; Mammal --TYPE_OF--&gt; Animal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capture a note on a tiger and Tangle immediately pulls up my previous notes on tigers and the cute cat videos I may or may not have watched a couple months ago. There are many more possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-friendly-machine&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#a-friendly-machine&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A friendly machine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tangle lifts a frustrating problem off of our shoulders so we can focus on the elements of work that are most important: reading, writing, creating, and understanding. The connections it generates are also &lt;em&gt;helpful&lt;/em&gt;. They help us to perform our work more creatively, help generate ideas, and keep our memories fresh. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until now, note-taking apps have required the burden of connecting old information to the present to fall on you. We think it&apos;s time to change that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are just beginning to explore the possibility of AI and machine learning in our notebooks. We are certain, however, there will be much to uncover. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- Tangle Team&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How a Fragrance Professional Builds Her Tangle]]></title><description><![CDATA[Two weeks ago, Cameron’s girlfriend, Alice, asked if she could give Tangle a try. While the alpha version of the product is still a month…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-how-a-fragrance-professional-builds-her-tangle</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-how-a-fragrance-professional-builds-her-tangle</guid><category><![CDATA[fragrance]]></category><category><![CDATA[connection]]></category><category><![CDATA[network]]></category><category><![CDATA[people]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago, Cameron’s girlfriend, Alice, asked if she could give Tangle a try. While the alpha version of the product is still a month from being ready, we figured there would be no harm in hearing what she thought of the prototype. After all, feedback is feedback and it was about time Tangle touched someone who was not its maker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, Alice actually started using Tangle not just for a few minutes, but daily. After confirming with her that her use of our fledgling product was not because of romantic bias, I asked if she would allow me to interview about how she used it and what her experience was like. She happily agreed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is the transcript from our interview. I have cut some of the verbal superfluousness for brevity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-interview&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-interview&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The Interview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Myles&lt;/em&gt;: What is your job title and what do you do on a day to day basis?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alice&lt;/em&gt;: I am a Junior account executive at a big fragrance house in New York. I work with 11 perfumers who are briefed on different ideas that we receive from our clients to create the fragrances they want. My job is basically turning an idea our client has into a fragrance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Myles&lt;/em&gt;: How does that process normally go?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alice&lt;/em&gt;: I basically just relay what the client wants and brainstorm with perfumers all day. They are what we call the “nose”. What&apos;s really important is having a full understanding of all the different ingredients and how they interact with your palate. There are over 5,000 synthetic and natural ingredients that all create different fragrant accords. A fragrance will be made up of any number of ingredients. Fifty to one hundred twenty normally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Myles&lt;/em&gt;: How do you keep track of all of these ingredients, smells, and clients?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alice&lt;/em&gt;: Taking notes and cataloging of all the different smells and how they make you feel is really critical to my job. You actually perceive smells differently depending on your mood, so training your nose to recognize those smells and the ingredients is really important. Writing all your perceptions down is obviously a big part of that training, but I am always on the go so I need something I can just write stuff down in fast. I also need a good way of making sure I am keeping up with my clients and the smells and ingredients I am using for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Myles&lt;/em&gt;: So what kind of system do you use now and what has made you stick with Tangle over the past couple weeks of using it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alice&lt;/em&gt;: So I had those little notebooks with the tabs that correspond to a letter and I would write down all the ingredients and how they smelled and interacted with each other alphabetically. But it kind of got tricky when I started filling up a bunch of the notebook and when I wanted to write about more than one ingredient. Like how two ingredients combine to make a smell. I didn’t really have a great place to put it so I would write it on a sticky note. I know Tangle isn’t perfect yet, but I don’t have to do any kind of organizing anymore which is really nice. When I am at my desk and taking a note after a meeting or about an ingredient I am checking out, my old stuff that I wrote down about it pops up. It actually helps my memory a lot too. What I have been using it most for though, is keeping up with clients. I use it kind of like a CRM, except I just write about the client and put their name in the note I am capturing and it will just connect to the other notes about that client I have. And, if I have written about an ingredient and a client, all my notes about those two things pop up when I am searching for one or the other, which is really useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Myles&lt;/em&gt;: Do you use tags or any method of making sure your related notes and ideas that you drop into Tangle are connected?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alice&lt;/em&gt;: Sometimes. So normally for client stuff I will just write their names and make sure they are spelled right. I noticed that if you don’t spell their name right it won’t connect. But, for ingredients, I use “hashtag ing” which means ingredients to me. When I search for “hashtag ing” or write a note using it, I get all my ingredient stuff automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Myles&lt;/em&gt;: Cool - well thank you I really appreciate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was great to get Alice’s feedback as we continue to build toward our alpha release. We are excited that she got value out the connections Tangle surfaced. We continue to integrate new features like “fuzzy matching” to address the spelling issue she brought up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking forward to putting Tangle in your hands soon. You can sign-up for the alpha release &lt;a href=&quot;https://ventures.us17.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=710569ad280cf37e55faa0612&amp;#x26;id=1f711ff76c&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- Tangle Team&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How Tangle Puts Connection First]]></title><description><![CDATA[In  our last post , we discussed some of the problematic design and organizational principles we see in current knowledge management…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-how-tangle-puts-connection</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-how-tangle-puts-connection</guid><category><![CDATA[knowledge]]></category><category><![CDATA[management]]></category><category><![CDATA[tools]]></category><category><![CDATA[tangle]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://usetangle.com/blog-tools-of-the-trade&quot;&gt;our last post&lt;/a&gt;, we discussed some of the problematic design and organizational principles we see in current knowledge management solutions. In this post, we transition to how the &lt;a href=&quot;http://usetangle.com/team&quot;&gt;Tangle team&lt;/a&gt; plans on correcting these issues with connection-first design. Don’t forget to &lt;a href=&quot;https://ventures.us17.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=710569ad280cf37e55faa0612&amp;#x26;id=1f711ff76c&quot;&gt;sign up&lt;/a&gt; for early access to our alpha release!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;rethinking-skeuomorphism&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#rethinking-skeuomorphism&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rethinking skeuomorphism&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might remember a specific design theory called skeuomorphism from &lt;a href=&quot;https://usetangle.com/blog-tools-of-the-trade&quot;&gt;last week’s post&lt;/a&gt;. If you don’t remember, skeuomorphism is the transplanting of physical themes onto a digital environment. It brought us the digital legal pad and pixelated sticky notes that we have been using forever. While skeuomorphic design is naturally familiar and accessible, it’s elements do not necessarily empower the user with the tools or behaviors she needs to be the most productive, creative, or innovative. We believe the benefits of technology and ease-of-use do not have to be mutually exclusive in product design.&lt;br&gt;
To solve this problem, we decided to flip the paradigm 180°. Instead of designing a product that mimics the feature set and organizational limits of physical items, we are designing Tangle to help complement, optimize, and support our core thought processes.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary function of our mind we are focusing on is its ability to make connections between information, explicitly or implicitly related, old and new. Our ability to make connections is crucial to our analytical thinking, creativity, and general intelligence. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The existing sea of personal knowledge management tools, however, don’t put connection first. They encourage manual curation and for the most part, will only help make connections after tedious organizational work that leaves the content in linearly structured files and folders. This organization necessitates frequent and cumbersome updating to maintain. The requisite work has even given rise to a consulting industry that teaches people how to make the most of digital PKM tools; connectivity being one of the lessons taught. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tiago Forte, an expert in personal knowledge management and productivity, describes our very humanity as &lt;a href=&quot;https://praxis.fortelabs.co/a-pattern-recognition-theory-of-mind/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;“the sum of our connectivity,”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  which rings true at even a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2010/02/100222161843.htm&quot;&gt;physiological level&lt;/a&gt;. To help improve the outcome of this equation, we are building Tangle with &lt;em&gt;connection-first&lt;/em&gt; design principles and with features that encourage connective practices and behaviors. Tangle lowers the hurdle over which you must jump to get the most out of the notes, ideas, and tasks you capture. Best practices are built-in; no assembly required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;connection-first&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#connection-first&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;Connection first&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tangle’s design facilitates three core actions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find explicit and implicit relationships within your information.&lt;/strong&gt; Intentionally and automatically drawing connections between information helps turn it into knowledge. A pivotal step in making individuals and teams more effective and creative. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep your working memory “fresh.”&lt;/strong&gt; Humans naturally forget things. Active reflection — re-reading old notes and ideas — will make more of what you know top-of-mind and useable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Insert randomness into your workflows.&lt;/strong&gt; Entropy can be the key to unlocking a new idea or the &lt;em&gt;aha!&lt;/em&gt; moment when attempting to solve a problem, basic or complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These ideals are embedded in Tangle’s user experience. To achieve them, we completely scrapped the traditional concept of organization. Putting information in files, folders, and digital notebooks is self-defeating; humans naturally aren’t very good at it, and we often have a difficult time predicting how we will eventually use the information that we save.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of forcing organization on the user, Tangle creates automatic, visual connections between related information (e.g., meeting notes, an idea, or a to-do). These visual connections replace the need for manual organization. Tangle accomplishes this using something called entity extraction: the system identifies key-terms and searches for other information you have captured with those same or related terms. It then connects the information in real-time on the screen using a graphical interface. It becomes immediately clear why two things are connected. The experience of &lt;em&gt;“connecting the dots”&lt;/em&gt; after capturing a bit of information helps strengthen the connections between what you know and refreshes your working memory. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tangle also encourages you to make your own connections. You can make explicit connections between the information you capture using hashtags as well as a feature we call Brainstorm mode. &lt;strong&gt;More on that in posts to come...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tangle is currently in its infancy. Like us, it will become more intelligent as it gets older. Eventually, it will be able to connect the dots between your implicitly related information as well. For example, while they may not necessarily have a direct text-match, separate notes captured about two people may be recommended as a connection if those people share a commonality. You may capture one note broadly related to “technology” that mentions Joe, and you may have captured another note related to “technology” that mentions Jill. In the future, Tangle might recommend a connection between separate captures about Joe and Jill because the two are topically related. These “smart connections” will transform how you work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tangle doesn’t just surface connections when you capture new information, it also allows search. In traditional note-taking applications, a search will yield results that directly match the query. The issue here is that when we search for things, we often don’t know exactly what we are looking for, just directionally what we hope to find. So, rather than providing just traditional search results, Tangle surfaces a whole graph of visually contextualized connections including both direct and indirect matches. Just toggle to the search bar and enter a query like you would a search engine. Easy. To drive the point home, there is no responsibility on you to organize your information, Tangle does it automatically, and keeps all of your connected knowledge at the tip of your finger. Search, explore, and find the connections that can make you a more creative thinker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, one of our favorite features is what we call the “surprise me” button. Press it and Tangle presents you with something random you have captured in the past. Tangle’s canvas becomes a map whose destination changes at every click; you’ll never know what you might find. This functionality is an ideal way to inject some entropy into your workflow, aiding the creative process and splashing your working memory’s face with some cool water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-mission&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-mission&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;The mission&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our mission is to empower everyone to capture and connect their thoughts to create big ideas.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tangle is merely the tool to help us achieve this goal. We have done away with the skeuomorphic design principles that we believe prevents people from making connections, keeping their memories fresh, and being the creative thinkers that will make them successful in today’s knowledge society. Instead of designing for familiarity, we have designed Tangle to support our core thought processes with connection-first principles. Tangle replaces organization with connection, removing the burden of self-curation and helping you focus on what is most important: learning and creating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to sign up for the alpha and haven’t yet? &lt;a href=&quot;https://ventures.us17.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=710569ad280cf37e55faa0612&amp;#x26;id=1f711ff76c&quot;&gt;Don’t miss out -- there are still a few spots left.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- Tangle team  &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Tools of The Trade]]></title><description><![CDATA[In  our last post , we described a general framework for personal knowledge management, its history, and how it has changed. In this post…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-tools-of-the-trade</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-tools-of-the-trade</guid><category><![CDATA[knowledge]]></category><category><![CDATA[management]]></category><category><![CDATA[tools]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://usetangle.com/blog-what-is-pkm&quot;&gt;our last post&lt;/a&gt;, we described a general framework for personal knowledge management, its history, and how it has changed. In this post, we’ll take a deep dive into the sea of knowledge management tools that has grown adjacent to our knowledge society.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-and-old&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#new-and-old&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;New and Old&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While PKM technology, as it stands, is not particularly ‘sexy’, it’s an increasingly important space. Almost every knowledge worker today uses some form of note-taking, task management, or mind-mapping software on a daily basis. Yet, for the thousands of these apps developed, and the millions of users that interact with them, they look largely the same as they did ten years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/usetangle-static-assets/blog/onenote.png&quot; alt=&quot;OneNote&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;OneNote in 2017 (left) vs 2005 (right)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is problematic. Knowledge work is the present and the future; technologies that manage and optimize what we know are paramount to the success of the 21st century worker; from software engineers to freelance designers to strategy consultants. Tools for externalizing our thoughts, ideas, meeting notes, and task lists must keep up with the rigorous demands of knowledge work. Knowledge management software should make the worker more productive, more intelligent, and more creative than before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The users of these products are demanding more too. Go to the forums for many of the top note-taking software sites and you will find feature requests, bug reports, and complaints from passionate users who insert their most prized intellectual possessions into their digital thought repositories. It is clear that there is plenty of room to innovate and improve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-skeuomorphic-legacy&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#a-skeuomorphic-legacy&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;A skeuomorphic legacy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One design element that you can find in almost any personal knowledge management tool is skeuomorphism. Skeuomorphic design takes cues from the real-world and is themed to be reminiscent of a more physical experience. Look no further than Google Keep, Evernote, or OneNote and you will see the digital manifestation of the physical; a pixelated sticky note, tabular binder, or notebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skeuomorphic design does have its benefits. It is fun, makes the user interface tactile, and is accessible. It provides the user with an intuition about how the underlying system works; if a user writes notes in a file, she will probably know to save it in a folder. Easy and user-friendly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, skeuomorphism also presents challenges. By transplanting physical designs onto the screen, we aren’t necessarily optimizing for a digital environment, but rather for familiarity. Making an interface friendly and the user experience delightful are aspirations for which technologists ought to strive, but design should be executed to empower the end user, not in the name of the technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We feel this distinction is incredibly important and has been missed by many within the PKM space. What is the goal at hand? What is the point of a note-taking tool? We believe the answer should be an external system that helps the user be more prepared, innovative, and creative. A legal pad certainly helps in the physical realm, but it’s also limited by the very domain it is meant for; why chain ourselves to desk artifact UX and UI design?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;linear-organization&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#linear-organization&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;Linear organization&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the skeuomorphic design that has widely dominated PKM tools, particularly of the note-taking variety, has been a primary contributor to UX principles that, we believe, move the technologies further away from their goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The principle to which I am referring is &lt;strong&gt;linear organization.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users are forced to organize the content they produce within PKM tools in order to make the information useful. The onus is on the user to know where that input should go. This is rather self-defeating: by siloing a thought, information, or notes in a named folder, that input has no opportunity to connect or socialize with anything that may be related to it. This leaves the responsibility on the user to remember what other content they have that is related to what they are thinking about now. Humans, unfortunately, aren’t great at remembering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of the organizational responsibility on the user, most PKM tools necessarily present the output linearly, or in lists. Files are in lists, which are in notebooks, which are in folders, which are also listed in other folders and so on. Listing thoughts out chronologically or alphabetically can be useful, but it is impossible to build a true “second brain” without visually emphasizing the relevant connections between the thoughts the user has plucked from their head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-fragmented-landscape&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#a-fragmented-landscape&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;A fragmented landscape&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is a visual representation of how we see the PKM tool landscape based on the principle described above. The coordinates we have chosen are meant to be relative; there are thousands and thousands of applications that do similar things, so we have done our best to choose representative ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/usetangle-static-assets/blog/pkm-landscape.png&quot; alt=&quot;landscape&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll notice that most tools fit on the left bottom half of the graph. They are organizationally intensive and linearly presented. Task managers, note-taking apps, and mind-mapping software as we know them all require organizational decisions. Tags, folders, labels, notebooks, projects; the list goes on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a subset of note-taking applications out there that emphasize quick content capture over general organizational capabilities. These look like Write Now, an Android App that allows you to swipe across the screen to open a pop-up note pad, and Papier, a Chrome plug-in that opens a note-taking interface whenever you press Command + T in the browser. These too, are highly linear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mind-mapping tools are the only group that fits above the x-axis. They allow the user to view the inputs in non-linear ways, hence why they are called “mapping” tools. They are great for visualizing a plan, network, or connecting related thoughts to a central idea. Mind maps are useful if you have plenty of time to curate a nice looking bubble chart, but for most of us who are constantly on the go, they are only used occasionally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;tangle&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#tangle&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tangle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, you will notice that the Tangle logo rests rather lonely in the top-right quadrant. That is because we are doing things slightly differently. We are creating a tool that mirrors how we think and, while easy to use, stays away from skeuomorphic paradigms and linear organization. Instead, Tangle grants connectivity first-class citizenship. Instead of making the user responsible for organizing their content into linear hierarchies, Tangle connects what you are capturing now with your entire existing corpus of knowledge, as well as any piece of information you may acquire in the future. Instead of showing you lists, it shows you connections, both obvious and unobvious. We are very excited to help herald a much-needed paradigm shift in knowledge management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check out our next post to read more about how Tangle is different than the rest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Knowledge Society and the Landmarks of Today]]></title><description><![CDATA[Following up on our  Introduction to Tangle  last week, we felt it would be important to write a bit more about the space we are tackling…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-what-is-pkm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-what-is-pkm</guid><category><![CDATA[PKM]]></category><category><![CDATA[knowledge]]></category><category><![CDATA[productivity]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Following up on our &lt;a href=&quot;http://usetangle.com/blog-introducing-tangle&quot;&gt;Introduction to Tangle&lt;/a&gt; last week, we felt it would be important to write a bit more about the space we are tackling and how technologies, like Tangle, fit in.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;knowledge-management-and-the-knowledge-worker&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#knowledge-management-and-the-knowledge-worker&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;Knowledge Management and the Knowledge Worker&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before diving into personal knowledge management, let’s start with where it came from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term knowledge management, or KM for short, is thrown around a lot these days. It is particularly hot in the enterprise context, where companies are clamoring to keep their organization’s know-how organized, retrievable, and secure as employees jump from company to company at a higher rate than ever. There is no standard definition that we could find, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kmworld.com/&quot;&gt;Knowledge Management World&apos;s&lt;/a&gt; is simple and to the point:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Knowledge Management is the process of capturing, distributing, and effectively using knowledge.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The roots of KM go as far back as 1959 when Peter Drucker predicted &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2014/10/what-peter-drucker-knew-about-2020&quot;&gt;“the shift to a knowledge society”&lt;/a&gt; in his book, &lt;em&gt;The Landmarks of Tomorrow&lt;/em&gt;. He suggested the most valuable asset of the next century would be knowledge, ushering in an era in which people would generate value with their minds more than with their muscle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subsequently, he surmised, making “knowledge work productive will be the great management task of this century, just as to make manual work productive was the great management task of the last century.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He called the agents in our knowledge society, knowledge workers. Simply, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knowledge_worker&quot;&gt;knowledge workers are workers whose main capital is knowledge&lt;/a&gt;. Are you analyzing, planning, writing, compiling, calculating, interpreting, diagnosing, reading, monitoring, collaborating or assessing? If so, then you are most likely a knowledge worker. In the knowledge worker job market, one would use this capital to market themselves for a new job. Today, it is safe to say that Linkedin is the knowledge worker&apos;s marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Knowledge” remained highly academic until the 1990s, when the management consulting industry popularized it in an enterprise context. As the internet and information technology developed, consulting firms latched onto the idea that they could use intranets and other technologies to facilitate easier communication within their own corporations, which led to time and cost savings. Knowledge management, in essence, became an asset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The realization that knowledge within a firm was the key driver for a firm’s growth gave rise to the need for new company cultures, taxonomies, content management, and ultimately technological systems to manage it all. Say hello to Salesforce and Atlassian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to 2018 and knowledge management is hotter than ever. Slack is &lt;em&gt;bloop-blooping&lt;/em&gt; in my headset as a write this and CRM tools are being gobbled up by seemingly everyone. Maintaining corporate knowledge is a big priority. There is even a relatively new executive position at some companies called Chief Knowledge Officer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;moving-to-personal-knowledge-management&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#moving-to-personal-knowledge-management&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;Moving to Personal Knowledge Management&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you read last week’s post, &lt;a href=&quot;http://usetangle.com/blog-introducing-tangle&quot;&gt;Introducing Tangle&lt;/a&gt;, you may have glanced the word personal preceding “knowledge management.” Personal knowledge management, or PKM for short, is a bit late to the scene and similarly to its big sister, does not seem to have a set definition. In general, it is centered around &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1057/ori.2009.11&quot;&gt;two fundamental points&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Managing and supporting personal knowledge and information so that it is accessible, meaningful and valuable to the individual.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Maintaining networks, contacts, and communities, as well as making life easier and more enjoyable by exploiting personal capital.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personal KM can be further broken down into a collection of processes that a knowledge worker uses to gather, classify, store, search, retrieve and share knowledge in their day to day work activities. Where organizational KM frameworks optimize a firm’s output by attempting to both break down barriers between a company’s workers to facilitate knowledge share and erect barriers around the company to stop knowledge leakage, PKM provides a framework for the individual to increase productivity by optimizing what they already know and how they grow their knowledge base. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PKM has garnered considerable interest in recent years as effaced by the many companies and individuals offering PKM best practices and productivity coaching, not to mention the massive personal productivity technology industry (we will touch on this particular piece later). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are five primary reasons for the new interest in the space:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Information overload.&lt;/strong&gt; We are living in a world of ubiquitous content. We need a system to synthesize, store, combine, and transform this information into knowledge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Technology.&lt;/strong&gt; The advent of task management, note-taking, and mind-mapping software tools have subsequently made people interested in personal knowledge management and productivity practices. We believe, however, that there is still a long way to go until we truly come close to solving knowledge management in the Information Age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The freelance economy.&lt;/strong&gt; The 21st century has provided the knowledge worker the tools to be able to work from anywhere. In 2016, there were 55 million freelancers in the United States. That is or 35% of the workforce. Freelancers produce deliverables just like the average employee, but their status as “my own boss” often leaves them without the existing corporate infrastructure and social incentives to be highly productive. PKM practices can help the individual operate as effectively as a corporation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hyper-competitive job market.&lt;/strong&gt; The rise of professional media sites like Linkedin means more availability of information on a higher supply of workers from which any company can choose. Being a productive knowledge worker is crucial to standing out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Too much to do, too little time.&lt;/strong&gt; Employees are inundated with projects. David Allen, the author of &lt;a href=&quot;https://gettingthingsdone.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Getting Things Done&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, has realized that most workers complain about “too much to do,” and yet most couldn’t give you, in the moment, a complete and accurately defined inventory of what they’ve committed “to do” if their life depended on it.” It has become abundantly clear that today’s employees need knowledge management and productivity resources just as much as the freelancer, and maybe even more than the enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The onus is now on the individual more than ever to be a productive worker, just as Drucker predicted more than 50 years ago. Personal knowledge management is a burgeoning field because it attempts to answer the timely productivity question from a bottom-up perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;pkm-a-framework&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#pkm-a-framework&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;PKM: A Framework&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many different frameworks for PKM, but one of the ones we like best is from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.knowledgeresources.ca/about/&quot;&gt;Dr. Kirby Wright, author of Rethinking Knowlege Work&lt;/a&gt;. We subscribe to the framework because it does a good job including both &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Personal_information_management&quot;&gt;information management&lt;/a&gt; and knowledge management practices in a clear way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He describes four core areas of personal knowledge management dimensions with which knowledge workers engage on a daily basis to solve problems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intensive analytical processes &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accessing and applying information resources&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social interactions and collaboration&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuous learning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of us approaches these four dimensions of how we work in different ways; our practices are influenced by our personalities, strengths and weaknesses, social factors, and our organization’s (if part of one) culture and context. The four domains are synthesized below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/usetangle-static-assets/blog/kirby.png&quot; alt=&quot;kirby&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These four dimensions do not appear in isolation; they are contextual, combinatorial, and are enabled by our individual and social capacities. Moreover, our problem-solving competencies, and therefore PKM tendencies, are affected by a multitude of factors, including how novice or expert one is, as well as personality, internal motivation, and education. The ability for knowledge workers to develop relationships and find common interests and understandings is also important to how one operates within the grid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the PKM and productivity space is comprised of practitioners that use these principles to develop tools, techniques, and methodologies to best support the knowledge worker. David Allen&apos;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://gettingthingsdone.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Getting Things Done&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the original PKM manifesto, which has preceded many other productivity and PKM practitioners like &lt;a href=&quot;http://learn.fortelabs.co/&quot;&gt;Tiago Forte&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@stevenbjohnson&quot;&gt;Steven Johnson&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These practitioners have latched onto productivity products to help promote their techniques. There are now thousands of PKM products like task managers, note-taking apps, and mind mapping tools. These tools, and the companies that built them, have garnered a fervent following of users. Look no further than &lt;a href=&quot;https://discussion.evernote.com/forum/304-general-feature-requests/&quot;&gt;Evernote’s forum&lt;/a&gt; to find thousands of ardent note-takers arguing over folders and tags. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next post, we will dive into these tools, how they function, what value they provide, and where they could be improved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- Tangle Team&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Introducing Tangle]]></title><description><![CDATA[How we think While the Information Age we live in has contributed greatly to the proliferation of knowledge and access to education, it has…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-introducing-tangle</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-introducing-tangle</guid><category><![CDATA[problems]]></category><category><![CDATA[notes]]></category><category><![CDATA[tangle]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-we-think&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#how-we-think&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;How we think&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Information Age we live in has contributed greatly to the proliferation of knowledge and access to education, it has also proven to be a rather daunting place to live and work. We are constantly exposed to a deluge of media, all vying for our eyeballs’ attention. Such is the nature of the internet and connected devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, a universal truth remains: each of us goes through life collecting, synthesizing, organizing, and storing information. In fact, we are consuming more information than ever before. In 2017, the average person in the United States spent 12 hours per day consuming media. That is half the day for those of you counting at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While that figure surely includes recreational activities, it nonetheless means we are processing information constantly. We can thank our gorgeous brain for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/usetangle-static-assets/blog/brain-slice.png&quot; alt=&quot;Brain&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way by which we accomplish this feat is unsurprisingly not like stacking books on a shelf or filing documents in a cabinet. Rather, we can think of our brain more like a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brainpickings.org/2011/08/01/networked-knowledge-combinatorial-creativity/&quot;&gt;reservoir&lt;/a&gt; in which we put information, insights, and ideas that in turn combine and fuse to form new ideas. Our knowledge is naturally combinatorial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we all would like a larger reservoir of knowledge in which to swim, its growth can also be daunting and cumbersome. The more that flows in, the deeper and more expansive it becomes, and with that expanse comes a greater need for the connective tissue that permits navigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That connective tissue, as it turns out, is not only a powerful framework, it is also an important element of how our brains function. A California Institute of Technology study found that general intelligence resides in many sub-structures throughout the brain, but it is the degree of connectedness of those regions that has the most effect on general intelligence scores. The brain’s ability to pull together disparate information is crucial to our problem-solving and creative abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;where-we-are-today&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#where-we-are-today&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Where we are today&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way we do knowledge management today is fragmented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some transplant their knowledge into personal knowledge management tools like note-taking apps, some store it in their emails, and others keep it scattered in Moleskines across their desk. Others bottle it in their heads, surely suffering from leakage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that personal knowledge management tools are antiquated. Our note-taking software and even communication solutions mimic real-world stationery, folders, and filing cabinets. These structures are rigid and do not accurately reflect the connected way we think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The diversity of subject matter and know-how each of us has is at an all-time high, yet our existing tool suite has not paid the appropriate attention to build the bridges and tunnels meant to &lt;strong&gt;connect&lt;/strong&gt; the disparate segments of our minds. Without applications that offer an information architecture that stimulates linkages, both obvious and hidden, the chance for the fusing of old ideas to form new, and the connectivity that begets creativity, will remain muted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-problems&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-problems&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The problems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are four primary motivations for why we need to rethink the management of what we know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Humans are bad at organizing information on their own.&lt;/strong&gt; Our tools today force us to store information as files in folders. Deciding where to put things so to find them later easily is time-consuming, let alone taking into account the act of finding it later. There are courses and thousands of articles published to prove it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current tools restrict connections.&lt;/strong&gt; The mechanisms for saving our information are a manifestation of physical necessity in a digital environment. They act as silos rather than the connective tissue we need between what we write down. Humans are terrible at knowing the future, particularly how an idea or note one wrote might be useful today or a year from now. Why keep our thoughts, ideas, and writings trapped in a digital filing cabinet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The most valuable part of writing things down is coming back to them later.&lt;/strong&gt; This reflection is made difficult by the linearity of the knowledge management tools we have. There is no way to connect the new and the old, to draw relationships between what and whom we once knew and what and whom we know now. Our knowledge management tools shouldn’t suffer from recency bias.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Knowledge work is the new norm.&lt;/strong&gt; Knowledge workers, people whose job involves handling or using information, will continue to make up a higher percentage of the global workforce as technology replaces manual laborer. Even more importantly, artificial intelligence will replace procedural tasks more and more, making one&apos;s unique creativity crucial to success. There will be ever increasing competition amongst knowledge workers. Knowledge workers are the new norm, and to succeed, they need to act like artists: collecting, capturing, connecting, and reflecting on their thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-is-tangle&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#so-what-is-tangle&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;So what is Tangle?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A solution for personal knowledge management in today’s world of information overload and overflowing reservoirs should be holistic and connected. It should give you the feeling of building an explorable map. It should frequently elicit the dopamine rush of the &lt;em&gt;Aha!&lt;/em&gt; moment. It should automatically connect your current thinking to the past and not only seal the cracks through which so many of our ideas slip but bring them back to the surface when helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should not only make you feel creative but make you &lt;em&gt;be creative&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is how it feels using Tangle. We are building it because we believe in empowering everyone to capture and connect thoughts to create bigger ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;www.usetangle.com/team&quot;&gt;The Tangle team&lt;/a&gt; has been hard at work building our first iteration of Tangle, and we are incredibly excited to share it with you. At the beginning of July, we will be opening up our product for the first time to a select few. The aim of this release will be to get Tangle into the hands of you: the creators, the thinkers, the idea jotters, the note-takers, the freelancers, and of course, those that never found value in knowledge management tools before. We will be actively seeking feedback from you all, and we cannot wait to hear what you think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to get early access, please do so by following this &lt;a href=&quot;www.usetangle.com&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the coming weeks, we will be keeping you updated on our progress and &lt;a href=&quot;www.usetangle.com/blog&quot;&gt;any exciting news&lt;/a&gt; fit to share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We can’t wait to see how the Tangle community grows.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;www.usetangle.com/team&quot;&gt;The Tangle team&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Inputs and Outputs]]></title><description><![CDATA[This story is going to be a weaving one, so bear with me. It begins with Cole and Cam forcing me to participate in a company book club…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-inputs-outputs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-inputs-outputs</guid><category><![CDATA[Inputs]]></category><category><![CDATA[Outputs]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This story is going to be a weaving one, so bear with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It begins with Cole and Cam forcing me to participate in a company book club…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry, sorry, let me rephrase. Cole, Cam and I started a book club recently (I know, right? Nerds!). We are attempting to read a (portion) of a book or article every week and spend 30 minutes first thing Monday morning to talk about our takeaways. The first book we decided to read was Cameron’s choice:&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00TT1VLAO/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;#x26;btkr=1&quot;&gt;Why Information Grows&lt;/a&gt;. In the book, the author, Cesar Hidalgo, defines information as physical in nature and uses an information-centric lens to define why different economies and countries are successful, or not. It was a thought-provoking piece of literature and I highly recommend reading it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the most interesting part of our group discussion about the book was around what Cesar calls “crystallized imagination”: the idea that the products we create are bits of physical information encoded with human thinking - essentially, economic outputs. What contributes to these physical outputs are inputs like raw materials and labor. Classic Econ 101.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conversation transformed into a discussion about our own individual outputs. Our ideas, our work deliverables, our own literature, and how we treat others. These products become other people’s inputs, and by default, inform their outputs. Not only what their outputs are, but their quality, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a great conversation and made me rethink my initial reluctance to join the book club. In fact, the discussion, along with a call we received from a dear friend, Julian Griggs, made me rethink a lot of things, including this blog. This blog is our output and my baby. Once a week, for a few hours, I will curate this so-called newsletter and schedule it to be sent to all of you who unknowingly signed up for the blog by sheer luck of being my friend (haha). It’s content then becomes your input, you read it, internalize it and might think about it for a day, or a while. In Julian’s case, Will Minshew’s [personal constitution], as well as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brainpickings.org/index.php/2011/08/01/networked-knowledge-combinatorial-creativity/&quot;&gt;Maria Popova’s Networked Knowledge and Combinatorial Creativity&lt;/a&gt; were inputs that caused him to call us during the middle of the day on Sunday. He said something along the lines of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Guys, I read not only the blog and the article but ended up spending the whole day reading and writing about other articles that I discovered because of them. I really want to start a thread in which we can easily share thoughts on these kinds of writings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, we agreed to his proposal, and Julian sent us his reaction to another Popova article on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brainpickings.org/2018/04/17/erich-fromm-escape-from-freedom/&quot;&gt;Erich Fromm’s “paradox of freedom,”&lt;/a&gt; an article he found on brainpickings.org. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What started out as a book discussion turned into a much deeper dialogue on how each of us curates our inputs. I asked myself, what inputs am I consuming daily? How can I ensure these inputs are the highest quality? From whom and where do the best inputs originate? How can I get closer to them? And, what inputs are most influential to my outputs?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like your body processes food and turns its nutrients into usable outputs like energy and waste, our mind processes information and turns its content into knowledge that we can then use. It has become clear to me that in the Information Age we live in, curating the content we consume is incredibly hard. Our social media feeds are diluted with bullshit half of CNN’s website is clickbait, and the news we see on TV is inherently biased toward whichever pole that channel leans on the conservative-liberal spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took action today to help myself curate my inputs a little better. I moved Instagram, Facebook, and Snapchat to a folder on the last page (4th) on my home screen and completely disabled notifications on each. I will still check them occasionally for a humorous meme or if my future wife has finally chosen to DM me, but I think their place in the order of my inputs is better off in the background, rather than the foreground. I haven’t decided what I am going to replace them with (Snapchat and Instagram were on my home screen). I am thinking of a random fact generator, or perhaps the Medium app. I&apos;ll figure it out, but if you have any suggestions let me know!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To finish up, I want this blog to be a quality, positive input for all of you. An input that you process, if you choose to open it, and which may compel you to produce a positive, quality output. That output can be anything. Perhaps it stays personal, maybe you share it. Perhaps it is as small as a note to a friend, or perhaps it is as big as your own blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You decide. Just remember that your inputs become your outputs, and your outputs become others’ inputs.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Personal Constitutions]]></title><description><![CDATA[Watch your thoughts for they become words, watch your words for they become actions, watch your actions for they become habits, watch your…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-minshew-personal-constitution</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-minshew-personal-constitution</guid><category><![CDATA[constitution]]></category><category><![CDATA[minshew]]></category><category><![CDATA[principles]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Watch your thoughts for they become words,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;watch your words for they become actions,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;watch your actions for they become habits,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;watch your habits for they become your character,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;watch your character for it becomes your destiny.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everybody knows at a high level that life is path dependent. Two humans subject to the same event will perceive &amp;#x26; react differently based on their previous experiences. This is at least partially because the brain, and more specifically the neurons that form networks that we label the brain, exhibit hysteresis. Simply, we are stateful beings. And from far enough away, this is obvious. “Of course an individual born in year 200 b.c. has different ideas, opinions, and norms than we do today!” But the more people zoom in, the more they seem to forget. “How on earth could person x possibly not have the same reaction as me to event y???” But these state differences still matter. And they build up steadily over time, much like a river carving a canyon. Every day sediment is moved, and it seems insignificant. But over millions of years mountains are carved, and the result is anything but insignificant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are not our thoughts. But we do, over time, become our thoughts. And our thoughts are heavily influenced by our environment—an idea that has been recognized time and time again in cliches:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are the average of our five closest friends.
We are what we repeatedly do.
How we spend our days is our we spend our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally I’ve come to refer to the principle as: We are what we eat, but at a higher abstraction level. Who we are and what we produce (concretely &amp;#x26; abstractly; thoughts, behaviors, relationships, systems, projects, etc; collectively, our outputs) are heavily influenced by what we think. What we think is heavily influenced by what inputs we receive. What inputs we receive at time t are heavily influenced by the outputs we produce at time t-1. Thus, &lt;strong&gt;the effect of repeated inputs in your life compound over time.&lt;/strong&gt; Each human is like a snowball rolling downhill. We start small and are often given a direction (by our parents, by society); over time we gain mass and momentum, which makes it increasingly difficult to change direction. Habits that you’ve had for 10 years are harder to break than habits that you’ve had for 10 weeks. The narratives of your childhood reverberate in your head as the narratives of your adulthood. It is no surprise most of us become our parents, to varying extents. But we are not without hope. We do have the potential for change, and it begins simply with awareness of this feedback loop between your inputs and outputs. Once you appreciate the loop, you become empowered to make changes. First small, then large.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this framework in mind, I would like to introduce what I believe is my most impactful daily practice. There are two components:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deliberately choosing your outputs, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reviewing &amp;#x26; engaging with your outputs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I purposely refer to &lt;em&gt;outputs&lt;/em&gt; abstractly, as this practice may be used to target concrete goals just as easily as less concrete habits, thought patterns, &amp;#x26; character. Here I have chosen to focus on the latter. Re 1, in my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.willminshew.com/2017/10/24/why-write-a-blog/&quot;&gt;first post&lt;/a&gt; I explored the importance of setting destinations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Before beginning a journey, it is important to choose a destination. The destination may be concrete or abstract, but it must be well-defined. If it isn’t, how will you know if you’re off-track, or if you’ve arrived? “My destination is nowhere” is explicit, and so acceptable. But if your destination is somewhere, further definition is paramount. Even the wise men needed a north star. So it is with travel, so it is with work. A well-defined “why”, like a good north star, allows course correction and coordination, and serves to motivate &amp;#x26; focus all involved parties. Fittingly then, my first blog post is about why I am starting a blog. This post is as much for me, the writer, as it is for you, the reader.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But destinations are not just for travel and work. They are for all adventures we embark on, which includes everyday life. Choosing a destination in life is about picking your own direction. It means living deliberately, proactively. It means choosing to actively write your own narratives, rather than accepting the narratives handed down to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you wish to live?
What do you believe is important?
What kind of person do you wish to be?
What kind of things do you wish to accomplish?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is entirely up to you what you choose for your outputs, and even what categories those outputs relate to. This might sound daunting, but remember these outputs are not set in stone. This is not your one chance to get it right; they are not set and forget. They form a living document, and defining our destination is an iterative process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This brings us to component: reviewing is how you turn your time &lt;em&gt;t-1&lt;/em&gt; outputs into time t inputs. The review process is critical: this is how you complete the feedback loop between your past, current, and future selves6. You should not speed through the review process as though you were wolfing down a doritos locos taco. Rather, you are tasting an exquisite wine. Swish it around a little bit, let the flavor engage all parts of the inside of your mouth (brain).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does the phrase really mean?
Do I still believe it with my whole heart?
Have I been living in accordance with it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If something in there feels wrong, or you change your mind, or it just isn’t serving you anymore—get rid of it. Test out different principles or truths or goals, see how they feel, and then decide whether you want to keep them, combine them, or discard them. The more you engage your brain in reflection, the quicker &amp;#x26; more deeply the principles will be internalized in every day life. This reflection builds &amp;#x26; strengthens various connections within your brain associated with these ideas. Much like high-performing athletes build muscle memory, you can think of this time as building ‘neuron memory.’ The stronger the connections in your head, the more likely these ideas are to trigger in the future. Not to belabor the point, but the repetition &amp;#x26; reflection has second-order effects as well. The more the ideas are triggered in life, the stronger the connections become, the more likely they are to be triggered in the future. Eventually the triggers happen so easily &amp;#x26; often that it feels like you’re running your mind in debug mode. At that point, you won’t be able to get away from the error throwing when you violate one of them even if you wanted to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For concreteness, I will walk you through my own chosen outputs, which are largely truth-seeking or character-related in nature. I label my own set of outputs my “Personal Constitution,” to appropriately recognize it as a formal agreement with myself, and I try to review it first thing every morning. My document serves two main purposes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it is a single location where I collect my thoughts about what I believe to be true, what kind of person I wish to be, and what kind of life I wish to live; and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it is a source of feedback when I review it, both to question how closely I have lived up to my ideals in the past, and to plant seeds for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a deeply personal document, and while some elements I believe are timeless, others may only relate to specific, temporary circumstances I am fixated on or struggling with today. You may not agree with everything I’ve chosen to include, and that’s ok; these are beliefs and ideas that resonant &lt;em&gt;with me&lt;/em&gt;. You also may not fully understand everything I’ve included, as each line now holds rich contextual history in my own brain far beyond what words on a page represent. That said, I am publishing it to serve as a potential source of inspiration for others, and also as a filter for inbound communication. Unlike Franklin, Covey, Dalio, Peterson, et al, I am not here to espouse any particular set of principles. Rather, the point I am trying to make is at a slightly higher abstraction level: it is the daily practice of choosing, reviewing, reflecting, and editing one’s principles that is powerful. Not necessarily any particular principles in and of themselves (though for each person, over time, I expect some convergence to a set they find resonant.) My own personal philosophy with respect to finding principles that work for you is similar to how I treat twitter: quick to follow, and quick to unfollow. One piece of concrete advice I will give: try not to make it too long. I have experimented with all different lengths, and ~1 page is about as long as I’m willing to make it. Any longer, and I begin to falter on component 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final note: some of the below are my own quotes, but many are from others. I chose not to attribute them because the focus is on the words and knowledge, not the author.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Updated 2018-03-27&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be present. Accept. Surrender.&lt;br&gt;
Meaning and reality are not fixed; continually reassess. Nebulous-yet-patterned.&lt;br&gt;
Life has asked of you, ‘what is your meaning?’ How will you choose to answer?&lt;br&gt;
Be impeccable with the Word.&lt;br&gt;
Love is the Mother of all Virtues. Pride is the Father of all Vices.&lt;br&gt;
The world is my country, all mankind are my brethren.&lt;br&gt;
Trust is the most valuable asset in the world.&lt;br&gt;
Seek understanding; don’t criticize, don’t assume.&lt;br&gt;
Be emphatic. Listen. Observe. Beginner’s mind.&lt;br&gt;
The greatest fool of all is the man who fools himself, and you are the easiest person to fool.&lt;br&gt;
Beliefs are hypotheses to be tested, not treasures to be guarded.&lt;br&gt;
I don’t know what I don’t know. Embrace uncertainty and humility.&lt;br&gt;
Experience::knowledge::ignorance.&lt;br&gt;
Be deliberate with your time and focus. Before every task ask, “is this worth my attention?”&lt;br&gt;
Produce. Finding work you love is difficult.&lt;br&gt;
Act =&gt; observe =&gt; learn =&gt; act =&gt; …&lt;br&gt;
Feedback loops enable sums greater than parts.&lt;br&gt;
Teaching is the best way to learn.&lt;br&gt;
Defeating The Struggle is where greatness comes from.&lt;br&gt;
Everything looks like a failure in the middle.&lt;br&gt;
Have self-compassion. I am enough.&lt;br&gt;
We, not I.&lt;br&gt;
Appreciate those around you; be grateful.&lt;br&gt;
Diversity is the basis for collective intelligence.&lt;br&gt;
A man is revealed by how he treats the powerless.&lt;br&gt;
Reputation comes from consistency.&lt;br&gt;
You must be willing in your heart to begin again every day. Commit willingly.&lt;br&gt;
Perfect is the enemy of done.&lt;br&gt;
Patience. There are always more opportunities.&lt;br&gt;
All in moderation.&lt;br&gt;
Power with brevity.&lt;br&gt;
Habits over choices. Reduce friction.&lt;br&gt;
What am I afraid of today? Be honest with yourself. Be vulnerable.&lt;br&gt;
Recognize the importance of the next task. Make today a positive feedback loop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch your thoughts for they become words,&lt;br&gt;
watch your words for they become actions,&lt;br&gt;
watch your actions for they become habits,&lt;br&gt;
watch your habits for they become your character,&lt;br&gt;
watch your character for it becomes your destiny.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Principles]]></title><description><![CDATA[Importance of the team Building the right team is crucial to the success of a startup. According to CB Insights,  25% of startups fail…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-team-principles</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-team-principles</guid><category><![CDATA[team]]></category><category><![CDATA[building]]></category><category><![CDATA[principles]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h3 id=&quot;importance-of-the-team&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#importance-of-the-team&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Importance of the team&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building the right team is crucial to the success of a startup. According to CB Insights, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbinsights.com/research/startup-failure-reasons-top/&quot;&gt;25% of startups fail because the team simply was not right&lt;/a&gt;. Other factors like market demand for the product are obviously important, but uncontrollable. A founder, or co-founders in our case, on the &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; team member.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, many people have written about the importance of just &lt;em&gt;having&lt;/em&gt; a team at all. Paul Graham, the co-founder of Y-Combinator believes &quot;starting a start-up is too hard for one person. Even if you could do all the work yourself, you need colleagues to brainstorm with, to talk you out of stupid decisions, and to cheer you up when things go wrong.&quot; I agree... we are social beings after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, you need a team, and the team needs to be somehow &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&apos;t begin to provide a formula for this equation, nor do I want to. Cameron, Cole and I just started this company and haven&apos;t even told you what we are building yet (stay tuned!!!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I do want to share with you, however, are a few principles Cameron and I came up with when recruiting our third co-founder, Cole McCracken. We had attempted to bring on a fourth co-founder as well but were turned down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;cole&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#cole&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Cole&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is Cole in his natural habitat. Pixelated and barely exposing a public API. He speaks in Java and is a self-described abstraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/hex-blog-assets/Colezinho.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cole&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Successfully recruiting Cole is a big deal, a bigger deal than I think Cameron or I give credit. It is a big deal because Cole was previously a superstar at Linkedin where he was quickly climbing the ranks of engineers. He was respected, made good money, had a great work-life balance and most importantly ate amazingly. The LinkedIn cafeteria is one of the best restaurants in all of San Francisco. Unfortunately, we can no longer get a reservation there, but alas, we have Cole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the outside observer, Cole gives the team a few things Cam and I lack:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical expertise in search.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A guy like Cole adds a bit of clout to what we are doing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lunch recommendations around our office.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cole is an equal founding member of the team and Cameron and I wanted it that way. I will tell you why in another blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-him&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#why-him&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Why Him&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why didn&apos;t we go to market? Why not outsource Cole&apos;s function until we could get someone with more experience and tenure? Why not wait?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We asked ourselves these questions during the process, but through our discussions, became convinced of one primary thing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understanding how someone works, their strengths, limitations, demeanor, and style are more valuable than the sum of that person&apos;s skill. Most importantly, that understanding breeds trust, the ultimate asset.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cole is a classmate from Princeton. Cameron and Cole worked together on countless computer science projects, burning oil far past midnight on many occasions. As the two technical founders, they know how each other works inside and out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three of us lived together for two school years in an infamous quad of 8. Technically, there were two neighboring rooms, but for all intents and purposes, the rooms&apos; contents and their inhabitants were the same. This experience helped us fully understand how each other lives. I believe you do not truly know someone unless you have lived with them. I am not advocating a founder go live with their potential colleagues... but it wouldn&apos;t hurt either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, we each understand how the other reacts to tough situations. 6 am wake-up calls for spring soccer conditioning were not fun, but built comradery and trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking the sports analogy further, a team of good soccer players who understand and trust each other will most likely beat a team of superstars that are playing together for the first time. I have seen this play out many times in my own career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This principle, while not the entire reason, was one of the primary forces leading to Leicester&apos;s 2016 premiership triumph. They only had two stars: Mahrez and Vardy (many would not even put them in the &lt;em&gt;superstar&lt;/em&gt; category), but they trusted each other and had a chemistry and belief that catapulted them to English football lore. The stuff of legends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, understanding and trust are core and implementing the systems that ensure the team continues to be built on these principles will definitely be hard. We are excited to take on that challenge.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Opportunity Cost: A Framework for Modern Decision-Making]]></title><description><![CDATA[Cameron and I joke about opportunity cost a lot. Until recently Cameron has been splitting time between working on the product we are…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-opportunity-cost-convenience-economy</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-opportunity-cost-convenience-economy</guid><category><![CDATA[opportunity]]></category><category><![CDATA[cost]]></category><category><![CDATA[framework]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Cameron and I joke about opportunity cost a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until recently Cameron has been splitting time between working on the product we are developing at Hex and his thesis – a pre-requisite to graduate from Princeton and something he put off while &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rOwRHsmBB8s&quot;&gt;kicking a ball around&lt;/a&gt;. Cameron&apos;s perceived opportunity cost of working on his thesis when he could be working on our product is astronomically high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I disagree with him, however, and countered his feelings of frustrations with all the reasons why completing his thesis, and therefore graduating (read: in 7 years) had many more merits than he was giving credit. That conversation, though, is not the point of this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/hex-blog-assets/opportunity-cost1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Opportunity Cost&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I joked with Cameron last week, bringing up his &lt;strong&gt;lack&lt;/strong&gt; of focus on our venture when we went off on a tangent about the aforementioned opportunity cost. Our banter ended with us discussing our framework for outsourcing conveniences to third parties and helped us understand the birth the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.salsify.com/blog/welcome-to-the-convenience-economy&quot;&gt;convenience economy&lt;/a&gt; The highlights of this framework are below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;times-constant-cost&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#times-constant-cost&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Time&apos;s constant cost&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today&apos;s world, one can &quot;do work&quot; from anywhere. The office is now somewhat ubiquitous due to the proliferation of the laptop and cell phone. One can almost always create &lt;strong&gt;value&lt;/strong&gt; for themselves, their company, or their clients as long as they have a connected device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only can we work anywhere, but we can work anytime as well. There really aren&apos;t many traditional nine-to-five jobs even offered anymore, especially if you are a knowledge worker. And, even if you usually do get home early, you can always earn extra money doing something else online or otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let&apos;s take a leap. If you can work anytime and anywhere, then there is necessarily a constant opportunity cost to your time. This opportunity cost can simply be thought of as your salary divided by some time period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-practice&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#in-practice&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In Practice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using this rule, you can very quickly judge if it is beneficial to pay for a service (the convenience) or do it yourself:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it takes you 15 minutes to walk to the dry cleaner, drop your clothes off, and walk back, then the opportunity cost of your commute is your hourly salary divided by four. It costs an extra 10 dollars for Boomerang to pick up your dry cleaning. If the opportunity cost is greater than 10 bucks, then buying the convenience makes economic sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have the option of cooking and ordering in and the time difference from start to eating in both situations is for all intents and purposes the same. If the extra money you pay for ordering is less than the value of your time over that period, then it makes sense to pay for the convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this framework is oversimplified and is not revolutionary, it can function as a reference point to help you make quick, rational decisions and mitigate wasting time pondering what to do in a given situation.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reflection: The Modern Day Version]]></title><description><![CDATA[Morning Pages The bedrock of my day is an exercise called  morning pages  – a free-flow cup of coffee with myself, where I put pen (or, in…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-modern-reflection</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-modern-reflection</guid><category><![CDATA[reflection]]></category><category><![CDATA[machine-learning]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h3 id=&quot;morning-pages&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#morning-pages&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Morning Pages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bedrock of my day is an exercise called &lt;a href=&quot;https://tim.blog/2015/01/15/morning-pages/&quot;&gt;morning pages&lt;/a&gt; – a free-flow cup of coffee with myself, where I put pen (or, in this case, pencil) to paper and jot whatever comes to mind. Some days these are a stream of consciousness reflection on inspiration I’ve recently come across; other days a physical reservoir for project ideas that jump to mind. Though this has been a liberating habit of self-expression, it has the potential to be so much more…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/hex-blog-assets/morning-paper.png&quot; alt=&quot;Morning Paper&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First thing in the morning is when you are the most raw, intellectual version of yourself, brimming with micro-insights waiting to be captured! Wouldn’t it be nice if this collection of ruminations could be integrated over time and made sense of? And, even more, if all of this were automated? Vis-à-vis: the technical ability to finally do so &lt;em&gt;(cue exit: thought silos)&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
          &lt;div
            class=&quot;gatsby-resp-iframe-wrapper&quot;
            style=&quot;padding-bottom: 56.25%; position: relative; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&quot;
          &gt;
            &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/86912300?byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen style=&quot;
            position: absolute;
            top: 0;
            left: 0;
            width: 100%;
            height: 100%;
          &quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;enter-tangent&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#enter-tangent&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Enter Tangent&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we think of artificial intelligence (AI) and machine learning (ML), we surface PopSci applications:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Waymo’s self-driving Chrysler zipping around San Francisco,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deep-Blue besting the reigning world chess champion &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.espn.com/video/clip?id=11694550&quot;&gt;oldie but a goodie&lt;/a&gt;, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IBM’s Watson (and, I am quoting here) ‘destroying’ humans at Jeopardy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though the field entered popular awareness in the mid-1950s, the cloud has democratized access to the computational power needed to enable AI. Coupled with software utilities to handle large data sets (e.g. Hadoop), AI has seamlessly become a part of our everyday lives:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Siri, our favorite mobile personal assistant,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal search recommendations on Google, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile check deposits deciphering handwriting to text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be it FaceBook generating deeply-targeted (though, often unwanted) ads pertinent to your interests or Gmail learning from the sender of and words in a message to render you free of spam (thank you). ML, or the ability to statistically learn from and make predictive generalizations on data, underpins all of these technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;back-to-thought-silos&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#back-to-thought-silos&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Back to Thought Silos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within this realm, a personal favorite of mine is natural language processing (NLP), which derives understanding from unstructured text. In the ML paradigm, a computer is trained by being fed a set of documents with hand annotated rules, such as the part of speech of each word in a given sentence. The training data is analyzed and a model is generated that probabilistically infers the part of speech for a word in a sentence based on the word, the surrounding words, and the part of speech of the surrounding words. Just as we get better with practice, given enough training data, a computer will achieve high predictive accuracy at tagging new text. Moreover, this exercise can be extended to segment other features such as tense, named entities, topics, and even &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentiment_analysis&quot;&gt;sentiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/hex-blog-assets/syntax-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sentence 1&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/hex-blog-assets/syntax-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sentance 2&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when are you going to tie this back to morning pages?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perfect timing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the simplest version, my morning pages can be aggregated into text form and indexed in time order. Once our clever computer friend labels the features we’ve trained it to classify, the fun begins!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the goal of synthesizing our parsed text into an output we can glean insights from, we can, for example, use statistical tools like clustering (surprise: more ML algorithms) to lump our thoughts into common themes. Recency and frequency can be included as factors to give more weight to the Jocko Willinck quote you couldn’t stop writing about yesterday relative to the Buddha quote that appears once a year ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the seemingly endless number of schemas, this is the stage at which innovation swoops in to deliver summarized content in an actionable, digestible format. Although my siloed morning pages may be a jambalaya of thoughts, an automated reflection process can transform them into an effortless tool I levy for ideation, introspection, and inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Knowledge Workers Dilemma]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Knowledge Worker’s Dilemma Today’s knowledge workers need to be thinking and working like artists. Artists do not gain inspiration and…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-problem-series-knowledge-worker</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-problem-series-knowledge-worker</guid><category><![CDATA[knowledge]]></category><category><![CDATA[worker]]></category><category><![CDATA[problems]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-knowledge-workers-dilemma&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-knowledge-workers-dilemma&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The Knowledge Worker’s Dilemma&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today’s knowledge workers need to be thinking and working like artists. Artists do not gain inspiration and begin creating from nothing. They are continually collecting tidbits from the world around them. These tidbits eventually become the catalyst for new artwork. Leonardo Da Vinci is a classic example of this. He collected thousands of moleskins worth of notes and inspiration, which turned into pieces of art like the Vitruvian Man and Salvator Mundi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge workers, defined as professionals whose main capital is their knowledge, will continue to make up a higher percentage of the global workforce as technology replaces the manual laborer. Even more importantly, artificial intelligence will replace procedural knowledge worker tasks more and more, making one&apos;s unique creativity and knowledge even more crucial to their success. It is clear that knowledge worker competition will only increase. The new remote work paradigm will be an amplifier for that effect. Companies like TopTal have created marketplaces for knowledge worker talent: from financial analysts to strategy consultants to full-stack engineers. Knowledge workers are the new norm, and to succeed, they need to act like artists: collecting, capturing, connecting, and reflecting on their thoughts - then turning those thoughts into knowledge, the asset that makes them, as knowledge workers, valuable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating knowledge is not an easy task for knowledge workers for a few reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The modern knowledge worker does not have time for long-form note-taking. Throughout the day, the knowledge worker is doing something: she is reading, writing, creating documents in the Office suite, discussing, and collaborating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The modern knowledge worker is flummoxed by the paradox of choice when taking a note. Where should I write the note? In what file do I put this note? How should I organize it? She finds it difficult to decide where to capture a thought or take a note and does not often have the time to organize or find the notes already produced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When knowledge workers do capture their thoughts in a note, the notes they take and store are not dynamic. Digital note-taking applications today mimic the traditional pen-and-paper with the added benefit of text editing tools. There is no connective tissue between the things one writes. There has been recent activity from Evernote, in particular, to use AI to recommend tasks based on the user’s writings automatically. Evernote&apos;s usage of AI is interesting, but does not tackle the more significant problem: how to make it easy for knowledge workers (or anyone) to make connections between their trails of thoughts to inspire and surface new ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very act that reinforces and creates knowledge (reminder: a knowledge workers most valuable asset) takes time and is difficult to do: reflect on previous thoughts, ideas, and knowledge. The reason why this is hard is a function of problems 1-3, but providing a solution to promote reflection is another problem altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The knowledge worker faces these three issues every day, whether they know it or not. As competition amongst knowledge workers continues to increase, these problems will become more and more amplified. Providing an application that can differentiate a knowledge worker by optimizing their primary asset will only increase in value.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sovereign Identity]]></title><description><![CDATA[The It Would Be Cool If Series This week I am starting a new series called “it would be cool if  _ _ _ .” This series is going to be mainly…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//sovereign-identity</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//sovereign-identity</guid><category><![CDATA[self-sovereign]]></category><category><![CDATA[identity]]></category><category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-it-would-be-cool-if-series&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-it-would-be-cool-if-series&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The It Would Be Cool If Series&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I am starting a new series called “it would be cool if &lt;strong&gt;___&lt;/strong&gt;.” This series is going to be mainly made up of first-person stream of consciousness posts detailing technologies about which I am excited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first post is about one of my favorite burgeoning technologies: self-sovereign identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;it-would-be-cool-if-i-controlled-my-digital-identity&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#it-would-be-cool-if-i-controlled-my-digital-identity&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;It would be cool if I controlled my digital identity.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time I am online I am giving bits of myself away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My email&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My date of birth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My gender&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My likes and dislikes based on my browsing behavior&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My attention&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bet companies like Facebook and Acxiom no more about me than I know about me. I bet the same is true for you as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be great if I did not have to give away my personal information, but instead provided access to it, when I want to, to whom I want. It would be nice to have a key, or token that I can lend, but always have the right to take back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be really cool to participate economically in the marketing supply chain. I, perhaps controversially, really enjoy an actionable advertisement - one that might lead me to a purchase. I like to spend my money on great products, and if I am shown a great product that provides me utility, well that is just dandy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertising networks and platforms need my data to serve me those great ads. Today they just take it - either through my browsing history (cookies), or the personal data they force me to enter it to use certain websites. However, much of the segmenting data they collect is inferred probabilistically. I google champions league scores and my IP address is in NYC so I probably like soccer and I might want to purchase New York Red Bulls tickets. I am served an NYRB ad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital advertising companies see that I have purchased Rag &amp;#x26; Bone jeans, buy 30 racks of beer once in a while, and use seamless a lot. They know other 20 something millennials also show these characteristics. I am therefore segmented as such and served ads that advertisers think I might like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I’d love to invert this advertising paradigm. I currently get served ads that people think I like, but I really do not. The most frustrating of all is when I have already purchased a specific item, and then I am served ads to purchase it again immediately after. Ugh!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, let me lend you my data, all of it. Who I am, my age, my preferences, what I am in the market for, what I like to eat, my income level, the activities I like to do on the weekends. Note, lend, not give. I still control my data, and I can take away access at any time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To rent my perfect data, you ma cherie, will pay me something. Whenever you take my attention, which will be often because you are now able to serve me amazing advertisements for products and experiences that I will almost certainly be tempted to buy, I should get something. After all, you make money off every click, and I am the enabler. Even cooler, you can now more accurately attribute what touchpoint in the advertising journey was the crucial one to my purchase decision. If you know that, you my ad serving guru executive genius friend, can charge more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magic!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now to the next level. Let’s say I lend you my data for $X today. After a month of serving me advertisements you &lt;strong&gt;know&lt;/strong&gt; I will like, I have purchased nothing. Well, according to the pricing laws of supply and demand, my information as a consumer is not as in demand anymore while the supply has remained constant. You, you little advertiser you, could negotiate my price down say 5%. Now my data is valued at $X(0.95). Now we are both happy again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Property rights are sweet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even a level beyond that, sovereign digital identity actually expands a website domain&apos;s business model. A publisher could both pay me for my beautiful data &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; offer me the option to not provide my data, but pay for their content. Many premium publishers like the Washington Post and New York Times are already doing this. Now you can optimize both of the traditional online business models: pay per click and subscription.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to a new, better attention-based economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, it would be really cool if I could control my digital identity and data. I would like to permission it to you for a reasonable price. The investment on your part should pay off in spades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, so I really did not explain any technology specifically here, but that is on purpose. Many others are working on, or have explained this concept much better than I can, and in far more detail than I have time to describe. If you would like to know more about self-sovereign identity, check out the links below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coindesk.com/path-self-sovereign-identity/&quot;&gt;https://www.coindesk.com/path-self-sovereign-identity/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.computerworld.com/article/3244128/security/how-blockchain-makes-self-sovereign-identities-possible.html&quot;&gt;https://www.computerworld.com/article/3244128/security/how-blockchain-makes-self-sovereign-identities-possible.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://whitepaper.uport.me/uPort_whitepaper_DRAFT20170221.pdf&quot;&gt;https://whitepaper.uport.me/uPort&lt;em&gt;whitepaper&lt;/em&gt;DRAFT20170221.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blockstack.org/posts/blockchain-identity&quot;&gt;https://blockstack.org/posts/blockchain-identity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bitsonblocks.net/2017/05/17/a-gentle-introduction-to-self-sovereign-identity/&quot;&gt;https://bitsonblocks.net/2017/05/17/a-gentle-introduction-to-self-sovereign-identity/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Blazing Trails]]></title><description><![CDATA[Vannevar's Predictions ... were oddly prescient. In a 1945 article published in the Atlantic called  "As We May Think" , the then Director…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-vannevar-bush-memex</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-vannevar-bush-memex</guid><category><![CDATA[Memex]]></category><category><![CDATA[Memory]]></category><category><![CDATA[Trails]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2 id=&quot;vannevars-predictions&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#vannevars-predictions&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Vannevar&apos;s Predictions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;... were oddly prescient. In a 1945 article published in the Atlantic called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/1945/07/as-we-may-think/303881/&quot;&gt;&quot;As We May Think&quot;&lt;/a&gt;, the then Director of the Office of Scientific Research and Development, Vannevar Bush, outlined the first version of Google Glass, a more advanced encyclopedia that we might now call Wikipedia, as well as something he coined the Memex: &quot;a device in which an individual stores all his books, records, and communications, and which is mechanized so that it may be consulted with exceeding speed and flexibility.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These predictions were born from Bush&apos;s concern with the changing relationship between humanity and the sum of our knowledge. He hoped that these imaginary inventions would help solve the information overload problem that he felt even in 1945.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bush lamented that our ability to distill valuable insight from &quot;the record&quot; was falling well behind the growth of published content. During the mid 20th century, developments in data storage were all the rage, but Bush saw another side to the equation: the need to place equal emphasis on how we &lt;em&gt;access&lt;/em&gt; information now stored on tiny discs. He writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mere compression [...] is not enough; one needs not only to make and store a record but also be able to consult it, and this aspect of the matter comes later. Even the modern great library is not generally consulted; it is nibbled at by a few.
[...]
The difficulty seems to be, not so much that we publish unduly in view of the extent and variety of present-day interests, but rather that publication has been extended far beyond our present ability to make real use of the record. The summation of human experience is being expanded at a prodigious rate, and the means we use for threading through the consequent maze to the momentarily important item is the same as was used in the days of square-rigged ships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering 90% of the world&apos;s data was created over the last two years, the question of how we tap into our collective knowledge seems awfully pertinent. As more and more content is pushed at us through a multitude of channels, how do we curate what we watch, read, and listen to? Maybe even more importantly, how do we store our own thoughts and ideas related to that content when our mental RAM reads &quot;DISC IS FULL&quot;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;blazing-trails&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#blazing-trails&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Blazing trails&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bush came up with a contraption he coined, &quot;Memex,&quot; which would theoretically provide a solution to this question. The Memex would help people &quot;blaze trails&quot; through their ideas and thoughts they capture in the device, keeping those trails for them so they could easily be found and accessed later. I do not usually like using block quotes (it&apos;s kind of lazy), but in this instance, I think it useful:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The owner of the memex, let us say, is interested in the origin and properties of the bow and arrow. Specifically, he is studying why the short Turkish bow was apparently superior to the English long bow in the skirmishes of the Crusades. He has dozens of possibly pertinent books and articles in his memex. First, he runs through an encyclopedia, finds an interesting but sketchy article, leaves it projected. Next, in a history, he finds another pertinent item and ties the two together. Thus he goes, building a trail of many items. Occasionally he inserts a comment of his own, either linking it into the main trail or joining it by a side trail to a particular item. When it becomes evident that the elastic properties of available materials had a great deal to do with the bow, he branches off on a side trail which takes him through textbooks on elasticity and tables of physical constants. He inserts a page of longhand analysis of his own. Thus he builds a trail of his interest through the maze of materials available to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And his trails do not fade. Several years later, his talk with a friend turns to the queer ways in which a people resist innovations, even of vital interest. He has an example, in the fact that the outraged Europeans still failed to adopt the Turkish bow. In fact, he has a trail on it. A touch brings up the codebook. Tapping a few keys projects the head of the trail. A lever runs through it at will, stopping at interesting items, going off on side excursions. It is an interesting trail, pertinent to the discussion. So he sets a reproducer in action, photographs the whole trail out, and passes it to his friend for insertion in his own memex, there to be linked into the more general trail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wholly new forms of encyclopedias will appear, ready made with a mesh of associative trails running through them, ready to be dropped into the memex and there amplified. The lawyer has at his touch the associated opinions and decisions of his whole experience, and of the experience of friends and authorities. The patent attorney has on call the millions of issued patents, with familiar trails to every point of his client’s interest. The physician, puzzled by a patient’s reactions, strikes the trail established in studying an earlier similar case, and runs rapidly through analogous case histories, with side references to the classics for the pertinent anatomy and histology. The chemist, struggling with the synthesis of an organic compound, has all the chemical literature before him in his laboratory, with trails following the analogies of compounds, and side trails to their physical and chemical behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like how Vannevar thinks about memories, knowledge, and wisdom. He sees them as trails, or branches, always growing and relating to each other in different ways as new information is captured, distilled, and stored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It reminds me of a tangle of vines through a trellis. As the vines grow, they wrap around each other to create a big, tangled mess. However, if you were to pull one stem out from the knot carefully, you&apos;d be able to inspect it, discover from where it sprouted, and know what other branches it had touched. You might even find something hidden from sight where the untangled vine used to rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is somewhat surprising that technology has not been able to bridge this divide yet. Our thoughts are structured one way, yet our data, knowledge, note, and file management systems another, forcing us to index these things alphabetically or chronologically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;hmmm&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-contemporary-memex&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#a-contemporary-memex&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A contemporary Memex?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have tried to find a product or thing, that fits the Memex description Vannevar laid out 70 years ago, but have not been able to find one that checks all the boxes. It seems to me that the cell phone or perhaps an application on a cell phone could be a Memex, but the way we use handheld devices today - texting, browsing, Instagramming, tweeting, calling(?), snapping - does not necessarily lend itself to &quot;trailblazing.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People should enjoy traveling back through their trails. We should feel delighted to discover &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; we came to know something or someone - especially when there is so much information being flung at us everyday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lawyers ought to be able to easily connect two cases at a deeper level than just precedent citation. Chemists should be able to explore how they reached a formula for a new compound. Not only the elite, but regular shmos too should be able to reflect on what we know and how we came to know it by having a wander down our trails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To conlcude, I will leave you with one last Vannevar quote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presumably, man’s spirit should be elevated if he can better review his shady past and analyze more completely and objectively his present problems. He has built a civilization so complex that he needs to mechanize his records more fully if he is to push his experiment to its logical conclusion and not merely become bogged down part way there by overtaxing his limited memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Problem with Note-taking: Reflection]]></title><description><![CDATA[In our last  Problem Series post , we discussed the problems with linear thought silos and why they make connecting the dots between notes…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-problem-series-habit-reflect-connect</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-problem-series-habit-reflect-connect</guid><category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category><category><![CDATA[Problem]]></category><category><![CDATA[Reflection]]></category><category><![CDATA[Connection]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In our last &lt;a href=&quot;https://usetangle.com/blog-problem-series-silos&quot;&gt;Problem Series post&lt;/a&gt;, we discussed the problems with linear thought silos and why they make connecting the dots between notes so difficult. In this week&apos;s blog post, we build on this narrative to explore why the current state of note-taking applications make forming the habit of reflection so hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-the-heck-does-reflection-mean&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-the-heck-does-reflection-mean&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;What the heck does &lt;em&gt;reflection&lt;/em&gt; mean?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great question. Thank you for asking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflection in this context means &lt;em&gt;the act of revisiting old thoughts&lt;/em&gt; and can serve a number of purposes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help you to remember either a specific thought or the context around why you captured that thought&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide you clarity on your current state of emotions or thinking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connect the dots between two disparate, but related ideas that you have had&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflection ultimately is like taking what we call a &quot;mental shower.&quot; You feel refreshed and clear-headed. You have filled in the gaps of your memory and may have added more critical thinking to something you are working on. It&apos;s like wiping the sleep out of your eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ahhh&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-favorite-reflection&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#my-favorite-reflection&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;My favorite reflection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotify&apos;s year-end reflection is all kinds of awesome. My friends and I love revisiting jams we have played throughout the year. We like the nostalgia of it. We love the sharability. We like seeing how our tastes change and, for me at least, how the songs we play inform a time in our lives and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Spotify mental shower is oh so refreshing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See? Reflection is cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-current-note-taking-tools-make-reflection-hard&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#why-current-note-taking-tools-make-reflection-hard&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Why current note-taking tools make reflection hard&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Information stored linearly or organized by a person inherently requires work. The user must curate and organize their files and folders &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; go back through all of them just get the water running from their mental shower head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real world manifestation of this is a notebook. You literally have to turn the pages – sometimes for a while – to achieve that feeling of reflection. Personally, the process is even worse in Evernote, email and other note-taking silos where you have to click through folders to find what you are looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe reflection should be incredibly easy. Reflection should be a service – like the one Spotify provides. Reflection should be a habit, but current tools do not make that habit easy to form or make permanent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hex Ventures is endeavoring to make the &lt;em&gt;ahhhh&lt;/em&gt; moment an everyday occurrence, not just once in a while feeling.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Problem with Note-taking: Linearity]]></title><description><![CDATA[In our first  Problem Series  post, we used Cameron-types and Myles-types as foils to discuss the three core issues with the state of note…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-problem-series-silos</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-problem-series-silos</guid><category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category><category><![CDATA[Problem]]></category><category><![CDATA[Silos]]></category><category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In our first &lt;a href=&quot;https://usetangle.com/blog-problem-series-notes&quot;&gt;Problem Series&lt;/a&gt; post, we used Cameron-types and Myles-types as foils to discuss the three core issues with the state of note-taking today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes are siloed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-curation is not easy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connecting the dots is work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, you are going to read all about what we think about those pesky silos and how they trap your notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes-are-here-there-and-everywhere&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#notes-are-here-there-and-everywhere&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Notes are here, there, and everywhere&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have done a lot of research and talked to a lot of people about what tools people use to jot down their thoughts. To avoid describing every single one, we have listed a few below in no particular order. I am sure you can relate to at least one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apple Notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reminder apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calendar reminders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email-to-self&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note-taking apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Docs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft Office Suite (PowerPoint and Word mainly)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dedicated notebook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stickies on laptop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scribbles in the margin (&lt;a href=&quot;https://hyperallergic.com/314053/leonardo-da-vincis-earliest-notes-on-friction-found-in-previously-overlooked-marginalia/&quot;&gt;shoutout Da Vinci&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I digress... The point is, people capture thoughts with a lot of different tools and more consequentially, in many different places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;linear-thought-silos&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#linear-thought-silos&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Linear thought silos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these tools become what we call: linear thought silos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These silos keep your thoughts trapped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We call them &lt;em&gt;thought&lt;/em&gt; silos because a note is simply that, a thought, captured as some form of data: text, image, audio, video etc. A thought is not useful on its own, but requires context and connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silos are often &lt;em&gt;linear&lt;/em&gt; because they bias the most recent thoughts you capture based on recency. When you open Evernote for example, the most recent file in which you you took notes is at the top of your notebook folder. Of course, you are able to search some of these tools, but from my experience, search features are only average or poor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;connecting-captures&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#connecting-captures&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Connecting captures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The act of capturing thoughts is useful but connecting the dots between them is what allows for reflection, provides clarity, catalyzes ideation and helps people frame their thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecting your thought-captures when you go back through your writings provides immense value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This becomes very difficult when you write down notes in linear silos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are taking on the challenge of stopping thoughts from slipping through the cracks.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Problem with Note-Taking]]></title><description><![CDATA[A foreword on the Problem Series This is the first blog post in the newly dubbed Problem Series, which will describe issues in knowledge…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-problem-series-notes</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-problem-series-notes</guid><category><![CDATA[Notes]]></category><category><![CDATA[Problem]]></category><category><![CDATA[Knowledge]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-foreword-on-the-problem-series&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#a-foreword-on-the-problem-series&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A foreword on the Problem Series&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first blog post in the newly dubbed Problem Series, which will describe issues in knowledge management as we see them. The series is not designed to offer solutions or answers to these problems, but rather provide you with the &quot;why&quot; and reasons we launched this ventures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be sharing our answers very soon...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-problem-with-note-taking&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-problem-with-note-taking&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The Problem with Note-Taking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note-taking can be an incredibly valuable exercise for anyone. Students look back at their notes to study, writers look back at their notes for inspiration, and professionals look back at their notes to just make sure they have the facts right. Everyone ought to take notes, even on the little things like their ideas and what they are thinking about. Doing that exercise can often lead to powerful insights and connections that might have slipped through the cracks otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To frame the problem, however, we have to start with the types of people in the world. Broadly, you can think of them as the Myles-type and the Cameron-type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;myles-types&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#myles-types&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Myles-types&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These types of people were never able to form good habits around taking notes or keeping a journal. They often tried, but it just never seemed to work out. They would go search for something they had written down and couldn&apos;t find it in their files and folders. Myles-types are not very good at self-curation and that discourages them from writing down their thoughts as notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;cameron-types&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#cameron-types&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Cameron-types&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These types of people are great note takers. They are organized, abide by standard naming conventions, and enjoy going back through their journals and notes to connect the dots. Cameron-types are good at self-curation and that makes note-taking valuable for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two types of people inform how we think about the problems in current personal knowledge management systems and where we think they can be improved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;we-identified-3-primary-issues&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#we-identified-3-primary-issues&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;We identified 3 primary issues&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes are siloed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We write our thoughts down wherever is most convenient at that time - meaning everywhere. Many people I have interviewed say they jot down thoughts in their email and send it to themselves, while also keeping notes in Word documents and note taking apps. This makes it very difficult to holistically keep track of all your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-curation is not easy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Particularly if you are a Myles-type, keeping your notes organized in files and folders is time consuming and doesn&apos;t always work out. Even Cameron-types would probably say they spend too much time making sure they know where everything is. Curating your notes also almost necessitates recency bias being injected into your organizational structure. The notes you took two years ago are lonely!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connecting the dots is work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The practice of going back through your notes, re-reading, and digesting things again is great mental hygiene and helps to frame your thoughts. To complete this exercise though, you first have to remember to do it, and then you have to do it. Those two steps are work. Shouldn&apos;t our note-taking technology help us to remember and surface our path of thinking?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;these-are-the-kinds-of-questions-the-group-at-hex-is-thinking-about-just-one-part-of-the-larger-knowledge-management-equation&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#these-are-the-kinds-of-questions-the-group-at-hex-is-thinking-about-just-one-part-of-the-larger-knowledge-management-equation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;These are the kinds of questions the group at Hex is thinking about. Just one part of the larger knowledge management equation.&lt;/h4&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Brothers Knowledge]]></title><description><![CDATA[We are what we know Humans, groups, and companies are a function of what they know. The more they know, and the more easily their knowledge…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-tacit-vs-explicit</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-tacit-vs-explicit</guid><category><![CDATA[Tacit]]></category><category><![CDATA[Explicit]]></category><category><![CDATA[Knowledge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Connect]]></category><category><![CDATA[Capture]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-are-what-we-know&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#we-are-what-we-know&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;We are what we know&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans, groups, and companies are a function of what they know. The more they know, and the more easily their knowledge is documented and shared, the better the organization will function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, where do we start?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s start with the brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-neocortex-is-pretty-great&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-neocortex-is-pretty-great&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The Neocortex is pretty great&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tim Urban at &lt;a href=&quot;https://waitbutwhy.com/2017/04/neuralink.html&quot;&gt;Waitbutwhy&lt;/a&gt; wrote a fantastic summary on how the world has been shaped over hundreds of millions of years and how humanity became the colossus it is today. It is a great read and I recommend it to anyone who has forty five minutes to invest in themself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The development of the Neocortex allowed humans to share what they had learned. When the Neocortex advanced to the point that humans could symbolically refer to a thing with a sound, it opened up a whole new world of possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We could now tell someone about how to make a fire, fix a roof, or how to make a spear for fishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huzzah! Knowledge could now be shared, and with this breakthrough, each generations&apos; starting point of knowledge became where the last one left off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-brothers-knowledge&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-brothers-knowledge&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The Brothers Knowledge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, our Neocortex gave us the ability to capture and share what we learn through language. But, that is not the only way knowledge is transferred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two kinds of knowledge. They are kind of like brothers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;explicit-knowledge&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#explicit-knowledge&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Explicit knowledge&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explicit knowledge is systematic. It can be easily communicated, shared, and documented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music, books, math formulae, videos, podcasts, and anything else that can be stored, retrieved, and learned can be considered explicit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;tacit-knowledge&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#tacit-knowledge&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Tacit knowledge&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tacit knowledge, on the other hand, is hard to formalize and capture. It is knowledge created by experiences, insights, intuitions, and observations. Being good at selling, for example, would be tacit knowledge. Acting with the proper etiquette at a traditional Chinese meal would also be tacit - you learn these things via experiences and your own natural intuitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;capturing-the-little-things&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#capturing-the-little-things&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Capturing the little things&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We at Hex believe that while many tools have been developed to help capture explicit knowledge - Microsoft Office, Evernote, etc - the way we organize and share that explicit knowledge can still be made much more efficient. Optimizing the ability for a group of people to share what they know will allow them to learn and progress as a collective much faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tacit knowledge has for the most part been viewed as uncapturable. We do not necessarily disagree, but where we see opportunity is to provide a place for people to save &quot;the little things&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Insights, tid-bits of knowledge and experiences that do not necessarily belong in documents could potentially be stored another way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We at Hex are working on untangling group knowledge so that more non-actionable ideas become actionable.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Sad State of KMS]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Human Condition We humans forget, are lazy, and lose more information than we retain. This is not helped by the attention economy, which…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-hate-files-and-folders</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-hate-files-and-folders</guid><category><![CDATA[Knowledge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Management]]></category><category><![CDATA[Files&Folders]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-human-condition&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-human-condition&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The Human Condition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We humans forget, are lazy, and lose more information than we retain. This is not helped by the attention economy, which inundates us with stuff. All kinds of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As consumers, we must &lt;em&gt;pay&lt;/em&gt; attention, attention being a scarce resource, to all sorts of different content - both online and off. The more information we consume, the more it seems we lose. Surely there is a way to keep more of this information, turning it into knowledge rather than waste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;enter-knowledge-management-systems&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#enter-knowledge-management-systems&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Enter Knowledge Management Systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drum roll...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;oohs and ahs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge management systems, or KMS for short, are what we humans use to store our stuff. We take it from the internet and save it, or we write it up and save it. We save stuff constantly, both work-related and non-work related.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KMS should make it super easy for us to do what the acronym stands for, manage knowledge, or keep track of the information that we have written or pulled from the internet and saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But KMS as we know it really stinks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When saving personal documents, either you are one of the 1% jedi humans who maintain perfect naming convention discipline and folder structure. Or, you are like the other 99% of us that and just hit &lt;code&gt;command + s&lt;/code&gt; and forget about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At surface level, it would seem that this is not that big a deal...just spend a couple minutes searching your PC or Mac and you will most likely find the folder, file, and information you are looking for (I bet Google would have been easier, though).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did I do with that file? Hmmm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sound familiar? This happens all too often and is really just such a bore! Now, think about the KMS for massive companies that have hundreds or thousands of employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time, thousands of folders have given birth to thousands of sub-folders - all pregnant with documents in all shapes, sizes and formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who is to say what goes where? Dave, who is my favorite generic cube hound, may have a different idea of where one file should be saved than say Janet. For example, the latest prospectus on the digital advertising market is saved down by Dave. He has plenty of options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe the &quot;adtech&quot; folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe the &quot;market_research&quot; folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dave might be a desktop kind of guy. The KMS is Dave&apos;s oyster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dave also has a lot of different ideas on what to call the file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Propsectus-adtech-jan-2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Market-research-adtech-prospectus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s been ten minutes already and Dave has finally decided on a naming convention and folder. Go Dave!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both options make sense, but when searching a company database, the naming convention can make all the difference between watching the computer&apos;s wheels spin or finding your document when you need to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;knowledge-management-irl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#knowledge-management-irl&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Knowledge Management IRL&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dave always makes me reflect on my own experiences. He is great at that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was an investment banking analyst, we had an absolutely massive amount of folders and files. It was my job to keep all these documents organized and retrieve the ones we needed whenever anyone asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, fat chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were sometimes hundreds of versions of the same document in a folder. Other times files that belonged one place had been mistakenly dropped in a folder that seemed related, but really wasn&apos;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular issue was especially bad on one project I was given because the previous analyst who worked on it completely threw out any inkling of organization when he found out he got an offer at a private equity shop. The next few months of working at the bank now did not matter to this young man, and neither did proper KM etiquette.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project I am referring to had died for a while, but randomly resuscitated (as far too many zombie projects do) and I had to scramble to find the files my team needed. It took me so long that they asked me to reorganize the entire behemoth that was the folder. It took me all night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will never forgive you previous analyst!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Files and folders do not work because there are inherent biases in any kind of shared curation. Imagine if instead of Google, it was Bank of America that supplied the search technology for consumers looking for retail banking products. That wouldn&apos;t work, would it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously not. The same kind of biases happen in file saving and curation. It is unfortunately too much for humans to handle and actually creates serious issues that can severely hurt the internal operations of a firm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We at Hex Ventures are working to help people pay more attention by spending less time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Professional Growth]]></title><description><![CDATA[A close friend who is now a senior developer at a large social network platform in Silicon Valley recently shared with me some some of the…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-boost-performance</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-boost-performance</guid><category><![CDATA[Performance]]></category><category><![CDATA[Growth]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;A close friend who is now a senior developer at a large social network platform in Silicon Valley recently shared with me some some of the things that she feels have been the biggest contributors to her early success. I thought I would pass these along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;take-ownership-of-the-uncomfortable&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#take-ownership-of-the-uncomfortable&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Take ownership of the uncomfortable&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there a new risky project with an unclear path? Is there an issue that nobody knows how to resolve? Don’t be scared and take it. You will stretch yourself. You may fail, but at the end of the day you will have learned way more than if you didn’t take it. Even in failure, this kind of action is rewarded by the best organizations - above all else, they appreciate driven individuals. If failure is shamed in these kinds of situations, perhaps that organization is not right for you...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more you jump at taking ownership of bigger, scarier projects, the more high-importance work you will be given... allowing you to grow even more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;dont-hide-weakness&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#dont-hide-weakness&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Don’t hide weakness&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While unbelievable now, my friend had a sense of imposter syndrome when first starting. As a fresh new college grad, she felt that her skills were not up to par, and worried that others (including the boss) would track her knowledge gaps and use them against her. This ended up being miles from the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nobody cares. In fact, most colleauges want to see you succeed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feeling scared and anxious about what you don&apos;t know actually hinders your ability to grow. Discover your what you don&apos;t, grab your shovel and start filling in your knowledge gaps by working hard. When you feel there is a gap too big to fill, ask questions! Never be scared to to ask for help, she says, it is the best way to learn and your colleagues will be appreciative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;sleep&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#sleep&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Sleep&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting enough sleep is an obvious boon to critical thinking and mood, but is often neglected by fledgling 20 somethings in every industry. She stressed that getting enough sleep improved her performance on the job and she felt she was able to learn faster than some of her fatigued colleauges that had either stayed late to finish work or hit the bars in the Mission. She stressed that you of course need to have fun, but it was clear that some of her colleagues who came from better schools and had stronger backgrounds were not doing as well because they were simply tyring to do too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sleep is your friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personaly can relate to this message well. During my time as an investment banking analyst, almost all the junior employees were sleep deprived. This led to easily avoidable mistakes, that in turn made everyone even more cranky than when they woke up after a week topping four and a half hours of sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subtract off a couple hours from work and add them to sleep. You will think quicker and better, actually adding value to your company.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Power of Thoughts]]></title><description><![CDATA[Humans are wasteful Every day, each of us wastes untold precious resources. I’m not talking about water, or clean air, I’m talking about a…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-capturing-micro-insights</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-capturing-micro-insights</guid><category><![CDATA[insight]]></category><category><![CDATA[thoughts]]></category><category><![CDATA[brain]]></category><category><![CDATA[storage]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2 id=&quot;humans-are-wasteful&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#humans-are-wasteful&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Humans are wasteful&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day, each of us wastes untold precious resources. I’m not talking about water, or clean air, I’m talking about a much more valuable commodity. I’m referencing the very thing that separates humanity from the rest of the animal kingdom — our thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;our-thoughts-are-powerful&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#our-thoughts-are-powerful&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Our thoughts are powerful&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human thought created the wheel, domesticated plants and animals, developed cities, and made us the most powerful species on earth. And yet, most of our daily thoughts simply evaporate into the ether. This would be understandable in a pre-modern context where information storage was restricted to our brain’s limited capacity. Storing every thought would have been impossible. However, that is not the world we currently live in. Today we have single computers that can store over a hundred terabytes of information and networks of machines that can communicate from all around the globe. Modern technology has solved the storage problem and with the right technology, we could offload our thoughts onto these machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;half-baked-ideas-can-still-be-yummy&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#half-baked-ideas-can-still-be-yummy&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Half-baked ideas can still be yummy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why even bother recording these thoughts in the first place? Aren’t most ideas half-baked at best? Yes, but a half-baked idea can be the seed of a revolutionary idea, if properly cultivated! At Hex Ventures, we call these amorphous thought jumbles: micro-insights. A single micro-insight is not likely to be fully coherent by itself and might not offer any obvious value, but consider what might happen when you combine many micro-insights together. Where one trails off, another might pick up. A gap in one might be filled in by another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-beautiful-mess&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#a-beautiful-mess&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A beautiful mess&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beauty of this phenomena is that it need not be restricted to the thoughts of a single individual. Imagine what could happen when you bring together the daily micro-insights generated by 10, 100, or 1000 different people. Consider what value could be derived from connecting these disparate ideas. Now envision a world where these micro-insights aren’t just coming from disconnected strangers, but are coming from a group of individuals working towards a common goal. What I’m describing is collaborative brainstorming applied to the thoughts we already have!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two obvious questions that arise:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, storage might not be an issue but how do we get our thoughts into it? How do we go about recording these micro-insights?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if we somehow managed to record them, how would we draw meaningful connections from a sea of randomness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leveraging intelligent technology to answer these two questions is what Hex Ventures is all about — and we certainly have some good ideas.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Non-Actionable to Actionable]]></title><description><![CDATA[In  my last post , I recounted the story of how Will Guier and George Weiffenbach’s discussion at lunch turned into GPS technology. I ended…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-non-actionable-to-actionable-part-2</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-non-actionable-to-actionable-part-2</guid><category><![CDATA[innovation]]></category><category><![CDATA[actionable]]></category><category><![CDATA[sharing]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://usetangle.com/blog-gps-story&quot;&gt;my last post&lt;/a&gt;, I recounted the story of how Will Guier and George Weiffenbach’s discussion at lunch turned into GPS technology. I ended the story by raising a series of questions regarding the opportunity for companies to use elements from this story in their own organization. Here they are along with actionable insights for taking these principles into your company or organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-can-we-implement-themes-from-this-story-to-spur-innovation-at-every-level-in-an-enterprise&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#how-can-we-implement-themes-from-this-story-to-spur-innovation-at-every-level-in-an-enterprise&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;How can we implement themes from this story to spur innovation at every level in an enterprise?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spontaneous collaboration can turn interesting ideas into tangible outcomes that bring value to your organization, clients and customers. There are a myriad of themes from Will and George’s story that can be translated into enterprise workflows - here are three that I found to be the most actionable:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Company as platform: The word “platform” gets thrown around a lot, but I truly believe that companies ought to design themselves as launching pads - platforms from which employees can initiate ideas, take risks, support others, fall down, get back up and ultimately, succeed. Will and George used the APL as their own launching pad to bring a an idea from side-project to technological breakthrough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connect, not protect: I have written previously about how companies can use Lisa Gansky’s concept of &lt;a href=&quot;https://usetangle.com/blog-connection-trumps-protection&quot;&gt;mesh&lt;/a&gt; as a principle around which they organize. Creating a robust support network at a company is vital to positive idea generation and smart risk-taking. WIll and George certainly would not have achieved what they did without the help of other smart scientists, engineers, students and teachers that were working at the APL as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investing in your people: time is money and money is time. Investing both in your employees and tools to help them achieve their goals will help a company achieve its own goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;investing-in-your-people-is-great-but-what-are-the-kinds-of-tools-companies-actually-need-to-help-them-catalyze-the-next-big-idea&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#investing-in-your-people-is-great-but-what-are-the-kinds-of-tools-companies-actually-need-to-help-them-catalyze-the-next-big-idea&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Investing in your people is great, but what are the kinds of tools companies actually need to help them catalyze the next big idea?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is not one tool that will take your company to the next level, but we think that tools that help inspire collaboration,not just through messaging, but that pulls individuals to meet and collaborate face-to-face are helpful for letting ideas bounce off and stick to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-can-we-structure-and-instill-organizations-with-the-kind-of-culture-that-led-will-and-george-to-explore-an-idea-together---and-how-do-you-make-it-repetitive&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#how-can-we-structure-and-instill-organizations-with-the-kind-of-culture-that-led-will-and-george-to-explore-an-idea-together---and-how-do-you-make-it-repetitive&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;How can we structure and instill organizations with the kind of culture that led Will and George to explore an idea together - and how do you make it repetitive?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no objective formula for creating a corporate culture that breeds great ideas, but one constant is empowering the individual to &lt;strong&gt;fail&lt;/strong&gt;. Empowering failure is the first step to success. From my own personal experience and anecdotal evidence from peers - all too often people are scared to fail. Humans are preconditioned to be fearful of embarrassment, but enterprises should instill practices that view failure as part of the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-do-we-make-interactions-like-the-one-george-and-will-had-in-the-cafeteria-repetitive-and-commonplace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#how-do-we-make-interactions-like-the-one-george-and-will-had-in-the-cafeteria-repetitive-and-commonplace&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;How do we make interactions like the one George and Will had in the cafeteria repetitive and commonplace?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tools and internal practices that spur collaboration, empower failure, and create an environment in which ideas are constantly generated and bounce off each other will inevitably lead to valuable innovation. One tried and true method for making positive interactions that lead to actionable outcomes commonplace is to design your workplace to be like the APL cafeteria - a space in which a diversity of ideas and insights can constructively collide, bounce off and stick to one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much has been written about how the design of a space can help foster an environment in which great ideas are formed. Homebrew Computing Club, Freud’s Wednesday salon and English coffeehouses during the industrial revolution are just a few of these. Perhaps doing away with the high-walled cubicles in favor of open space that invites rather than dissuades collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, company culture is ultimately derived from the how the people in charge interact with others in the organization. Setting a standard of open communication, support and encouragement will make it easier for valuable ideas to come alive and become actionable.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Story of GPS]]></title><description><![CDATA[1957 Great ideas, technologies and companies do not catalyze in a vacuum. They happen almost at random because of collaboration, sharing and…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-gps-story</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-gps-story</guid><category><![CDATA[GPS]]></category><category><![CDATA[innovation]]></category><category><![CDATA[actionable]]></category><category><![CDATA[sharing]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2 id=&quot;1957&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1957&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;1957&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great ideas, technologies and companies do not catalyze in a vacuum. They happen almost at random because of collaboration, sharing and cooperation among many parties. I think the story of how two scientists discovered GPS is one from which we can learn, and which we can emulate within our teams, organizations and companies to achieve valuable things/goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The global positioning system, or GPS as we know it today, started off as a side-project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On October 7th, 1957, Will Guier and George Weiffenbach, two students at the Johns Hopkins Applied Physics Lab (APL) were having lunch discussing the day’s most popular news: Sputnik’s launch into orbit three days prior. The two became rather excitable when they agreed it was likely that you could listen to Sputnik via the microwaves it was emanating. After discussing with classmates and professors, they quickly realized that nobody at APL had tried this yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It just so happened that Weiffenbach was in the middle of a Ph.D. on microwave spectroscopy and the 20MHz microwave he had in his office was the exact frequency needed to pick up the Sputnik’s signal. It turns out the Russians made Sputnik incredibly easy to listen to in order to prove that the whole thing was not a just a hoax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;buzz-on-campus&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#buzz-on-campus&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Buzz On Campus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon enough the entire APL had heard about the two’s discovery and passerby’s often stopped into Weiffenbach’s office to take a listen. Realizing that they were listening to history in the making, they rolled in an audio amplifier and began recording the signal as well - including timestamps whenever they recorded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After doing this on a few separate occasions, Will and George realized that because Sputnik was emitting a signal at a steady frequency, and because the microwave receiver was stationary, they could calculate the movement of the satellite based on the changes in the waveform they were capturing. Later that night, they also remembered that by analyzing the slope of the Doppler shift, they could determine the point in Sputnik’s orbit that was closest to the APL laboratories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost by accident, they had hit upon a technique not just for calculating the satellite’s speed, but for actually mapping the trajectory of its orbit. In a matter of hours, the two young scientists had gone from listening to tracking the Russian satellite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can imagine, this discovery made the entire APL buzz, and soon enough a loose network of scientists and engineers coalesced around the two twenty somethings, offering insights, new approaches and technology improvements. APL then provided funding for Will and George to use the university’s new UNIVAC computer, and shortly thereafter, they successfully mapped the satellite’s entire orbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-call-from-a-boss&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#a-call-from-a-boss&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A Call from a Boss&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About 6 months later, Frank McClure, the director of the APL, asked the two young men if they could flip the equation: If you could use the static position of the receiver and the doppler effect to map something in space. Could you then find the exact position of something on the ground knowing the exact orbit of a satellite in space?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make a long story short, the answer is yes, you can. And, unbeknownst to them, Will and George had created the technology that would allow the US to track their nuclear submarines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to today… the technology, now commonly known as GPS, has been made a public utility by Ronald Reagan. It is estimated that if GPS was shutoff, the economy would immediately lose ~$100bn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This story is both remarkable and admirable, as well as offers us a unique lens through which to view raw innovation: a 60 year journey from listening to Sputnik, to ubiquitous GPS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;questions&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#questions&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we implement themes from this story to spur innovation at every level in an enterprise?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe more realistically, what are the kinds of tools companies need to catalyze the next GPS?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we structure and instill organizations with the kind of culture that first led Will and George to explore an idea together, then coalesced a group of other scientists to bring the discovery from side-project to real breakthrough?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do we make these interactions and repetitive and commonplace?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;These are the kinds of questions we at Hex Ventures think about daily. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://usetangle.com/blog-non-actionable-to-actionable-part-2&quot;&gt;part 2&lt;/a&gt; to learn some insights we came up with!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Mesh Lens]]></title><description><![CDATA[Dinner Conversation I recently had dinner with some former colleagues, all of whom have been in both the financial and professional services…]]></description><link>http://usetangle.com.//blog-connection-trumps-protection</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://usetangle.com.//blog-connection-trumps-protection</guid><category><![CDATA[mesh]]></category><category><![CDATA[knowledge]]></category><category><![CDATA[sharing]]></category><category><![CDATA[ted]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tangle Community Member]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2 id=&quot;dinner-conversation&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#dinner-conversation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Dinner Conversation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently had dinner with some former colleagues, all of whom have been in both the financial and professional services industries for more years than I have been alive. We began to talk about how collaborative tools / knowledge management systems have never really worked at their firms (think boutique bank and big consulting).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was surprised by their pessimistic view of these kinds of tools — I imagined they would add a lot of value at companies that generate revenue from their knowledge and ideas.
So, I prodded and asked why they felt this way...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collaboration and knowledge sharing doesn’t really work in practice. It’s just the way it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, you know, the incentive structure doesn’t support it. Employees do not want others knowing what they know in an organization where salaries are structured with a base and revenue-based bonus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hmm.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-take&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#my-take&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;My Take&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The phrase: “It’s just the way it is,” makes me cringe. My subconscious translates it to “It’s just what everyone is comfortable with accepting”. However, in this case, avoiding a verbal kerfuffle was for the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the long run, growing the pie is a more effective way to earn higher compensation than trying to cut a bigger slice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I began to think about what makes a professional services firm better than another. What is the formula that makes any organization great? Is it that they have the smartest employees who know a lot? Or, perhaps is it how these individuals are organized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-rabbit-hole&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-rabbit-hole&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The Rabbit Hole&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day I went down a deep rabbit hole in pursuit of some semblance of an answer. The search was fruitful. I didn’t find any specific answers, per se, but rather organizing principles around which I could think about a company’s infrastructure, systems, and operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One concept I found particularly interesting was the notion of “mesh”. Mesh, the brainchild of Lisa Gansky, is a one-word descriptor for a company that focuses on shareability and leverages technology to track and derive value from customer data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&apos;aspect-ratio aspect-ratio--16x9&apos;&gt;
  &lt;iframe class=&apos;aspect-ratio--object&apos; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IHBGLHgIWJM?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put simply, a mesh is a sharing network — one in which there is a commodity that is shared, used, and shared again. Mesh networks becomes more useful and durable as more users are added to it. For example, the Airbnb network is strong because if one property owner unlists their home, plenty of options remain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, the network makes the company smarter as more users use it. Uber aggregates data on millions of rides a day to understand transportation trends, in turn helping them make informed strategic decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lisa’s concept of meshy describes companies that have been highly successful at leveraging a platform, scaling and ultimately, making money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-insight&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#an-insight&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;anchor&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;An Insight&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While listening to Lisa’s TED talk, however, it occurred to me that mesh could also describe the internal structure of a company. At its best, a company should act as a sharing platform — one that becomes stronger as more workers are added and smarter as more work is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this instance, what is shared is not a service, but rather ideas, insights and knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company becomes stronger, smarter and ultimately more valuable as the collective knowledge of the firm grows and becomes more connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making the internal workings of a company meshy means developing a culture based on individual empowerment, collaboration and reflection. This is a big investment, and requires the right tools and organizational hierarchy that fit the needs of your business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I believe the rewards can be immense. Constructing a meshy organization can propel a company towards achieving its goal of providing an excellent product, regardless of what that product might be. It is clear to me that connecting will always trump protecting - The more a company’s individuals are connected, no matter what the organizational chart looks like, the better that company can serve its clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our plan is to be our own kind of mesh, and help you become a mesh too.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>